黑烟囱……冒黑烟……
Chim chiminy chim chiminy
Chim chim cheree
烟囱清扫工就是幸运星
A sweep is as lucky as
lucky can be
黑烟囱……冒黑烟……
Chim chiminy chim chiminy
Chim chim cheroo
当他和你握手的时候，幸运就会传染给你
Good luck will rub off
when he shakes hands with you
黑烟囱……冒黑烟……
Chim chiminy chim chim cheree
Chim cheroo
All right, ladies and gents.
女士们，先生们
这样的场合，幽默诗正好派上用场
Comical poems
suitable for the occasion,
即兴创作，当场发表
extemporised and thought up
before your very eyes.
好的，我们开始
All right, here we go.
这是我们共同的天地
Room here for everyone
Gather around
The constable's responstable.
警察先生克尽职守
Now, how does that sound?
听起来还不错吧？
Hmm...
Hello, Miss Lark
I got one for you
你好，拉克小姐 让我为你献上一首
Miss Lark likes to walk in the park...
拉克小姐喜欢和安德鲁在公园散步
- Grrrr.
- ...with Andrew!
Arf! Arf!
- Hello, Andrew.
- An'! Arf! Grrrr! Grrrr!
你好啊，安德鲁
Ah, Mrs Cory
啊，考利夫人 一个关于你的故事
A story for you
Your daughters were shorter than you,
你的女儿过去比你矮……
but they grew.
但现在，她们长高了
Dear Miss Persimmon...
亲爱的帕西蒙小姐
Yes?
嗯？
Wind's in the east
风，从东方刮来
雾，在四处弥漫
Mist comin' in
Like something is brewin'
一件酝酿已久的事情看似就要发生
About to begin
没人能够预测未来
Can't put me finger
on what lies in store
But I feel what's to happen
但我知道将要发生的一切……
All happened before
都曾经发生过
Arf! Arf! Grrrr!
I'm sorry.
Where was I?
对不起，刚才说到哪里了？
Thank you, one and all,
for your kind support.
谢谢，谢谢你的支持
啊，拉克小姐，谢谢。
Ah, Miss Lark, thank you.
Crikey.
天主保佑你
Bless you, guv.
您就是慷慨的化身
Generosity itself, that's what you are.
您就免了。
No charge.
哦，是你啊！你好。
Oh, it's you. Hello.
你是说，樱桃树大街17号么？
Number 17 Cherry Tree Lane,
you say?
好吧，跟我来。
All right. Come with me.
This here's Cherry Tree Lane.
这就是樱桃树大街
一个很可爱的地方
Nice little spot, you might say.
17号就在前面
Number 17 is just down a bit.
Now this imposing edifice
what first greets the eye
这个能给人留下深刻印象的大房子第一眼看上去并不舒服
is the home of Admiral Boom,
它是退役海军上将
late of His Majesty's navy.
鲍默将军的家
Likes his house shipshape
and Bristol fashion at all times.
他的房子就像一艘船
他做事更是井井有条，一丝不苟
- Time gun ready?
- Ready and charged, sir.
报时枪准备 准备完毕，将军
- Three minutes and six seconds.
- Aye, aye, sir.
还有3分零6秒 是，将军
将军一向以准时而闻名
What he's famous for is punctuality.
全世界都以格林尼治时间为准
The whole world
takes its time from Greenwich,
but Greenwich
takes its time from Admiral Boom.
但人们说格林尼治以将军的时间为准
情况还好么，将军？
What cheer, Admiral?
下午好，年轻人。你要到哪儿去？
Good afternoon! Where are you bound?
Some parties want to see number 17.
17号那儿有个聚会，我想去看看
- Enter that in the log.
- Aye, aye, sir.
把这事记入航海日志 是，将军
应该提醒你，年轻人
Some advice, young man.
17号地区的暴风雨迹象已经很明显
Storm signals are up at 17.
天气马上就要变坏
Heavy weather brewing there.
Thank you, sir.
I'll keep an eye skinned.
谢谢，我会留神的
这就是樱桃树大街17号
Here we are.
Number 17 Cherry Tree Lane,
residence of George Banks, esquire.
乔治?班克斯先生的住所
Hello, hello, hello.
The admiral's right.
噢，将军的话一点都没错
17号地区的天气很恶劣
Heavy weather brewing at number 17,
and no mistake.
Leave her alone!
别理她！ 住嘴！
我告诉你，不要试图阻止这个恶人！
Don't you be trying to stop
the wretched creature!
让她走，我说，她走了真好！
Let her go and good riddance.
I never liked her from the moment
she set foot in the door.
从她踏进门的那刻起，我就没喜欢过她
But who'll get stuck with the children?
Me, that's who!
但没有了保姆，谁来对付那两个孩子？我么？天！
瞧她那高傲的样子！
Her and her high and mighty ways.
还有她那张脸，我已经受够了
And that face of her
that would stop a coal barge, it would.
事实上，布里夫人！你就是把全世界的财宝
Indeed, Mrs Brill!
I wouldn't stay in this house
another minute
都堆在我面前，我也不会再多呆一分钟
for all the jewels in Christendom.
不，不，卡蒂保姆，别走！
No, Katie Nanna, don't go!
别挡着门
Stand away from that door!
你让我们怎么和主人说孩子的事呢？
What'll I tell the master
about the children?
这与我无关。这是那两个小野兽最后一次从我这溜走。
It's no concern of mine.
Those beasts ran away from me.
They must be somewhere.
Did you look around the zoo?
他们一定在什么地方。你去动物园找过了么？
你了解简和迈克尔
你难道不担心狮子会抓住他们吗？
You think the lion got them?
你知道他们是多喜欢在那笼子周围玩
They're fond of
hanging around the cage.
我不想再废话了
I've said my say.
I've done with this house forever.
这所房子已经和我永远一刀两断
Hip, hip, hooray!
好啊，好极了
出门当心别摔了，宝贝
Don't stumble on the way out.
噢，别这样，卡蒂保姆！
No, no, Katie Nanna!
Mrs Banks. She's home.
班克斯夫人！她回来了！
我们女儿的女儿会敬仰我们 我们将一起欢唱
Our daughter's
daughters will adore us
And we'll sing in grateful chorus
"Well done, Sister Suffragette"
“干得好，主张参政的姐妹们”
卡蒂保姆，艾伦，晚上好
Good evening, Katie Nanna and Ellen.
我们举行了一场盛大的聚会！
The meeting was glorious!
威伯尼夫人把自己绑在首相的马车车轮上
Mrs Whitbourne-Allen chained herself
to the prime minister's carriage.
You should have been there!
你们真应该去看看 班克斯夫人，我有句话要对你说
And Mrs Ainslie
was carried off to prison.
还有阿什列夫人被抓走了
她一路上边唱歌边散发传单
Singing and scattering pamphlets
all the way!
我很高兴你回来了，夫人，我已经尽力了
Madam, I've always given my best...
谢谢你，卡蒂保姆
Thank you, Katie Nanna.
I knew you were one of us.
我就知道我不会看错的
我们是身着裙装的战士
We're clearly soldiers in petticoats
为妇女的投票权而英勇地战斗
And dauntless crusaders
for women's votes
尽管我们尊敬每一个男人
Though we adore men individually
We agree that as a group
they're rather stupid
但作为一个群体，他们是愚蠢的
Mrs Banks...
班克斯夫人 甩掉昨日的枷锁
Cast off the shackles of yesterday
肩并肩，我们走向自由
Shoulder to shoulder into the fray
我们女儿的女儿将会敬仰我们
Our daughter's daughters will adore us
And they'll sing in grateful chorus
她们将一齐欢唱
"Well done, Sister Suffragette"
“干得好 主张参政的姐妹们”
可能的话，我不想冒犯你，但是……
I don't wish to offend, but...
From Kensington to Billingsgate
One hears the restless cries
从肯辛顿到比林斯门呼声此起彼伏
从这片土地的每一个角落 妇女们站起来了
From every corner of the land
Womankind, arise
政治平等 权利平等
Political equality
and equal rights with men
Take heart, for Mrs Pankhurst
has been clapped in irons again
潘克赫斯特夫人又被铐上
No more the meek
and mild subservients we
我们不再做温顺的附属品
为了我们的权力英勇奋斗
We're fighting for our rights militantly
Never you fear
If I may have a word...
班克斯夫人，我能插句话么？
So cast off the shackles of yesterday
甩掉昨日的枷锁 班克斯夫人！
肩并肩我们走向自由
Shoulder to shoulder into the fray
Our daughter's daughters will adore us
我们女儿的女儿将会敬仰我们
她们将一齐欢唱
And they'll sing in grateful chorus
"Well done"
“干得好” 班克斯夫人
Mrs Banks!
"Well done"
班克斯夫人！
Mrs Banks!
What is it, Katie Nanna?
什么事？ 班克斯夫人，我有件事要告诉你
I have something to say to you.
Where are the children?
孩子们在哪里？ 夫人，孩子们……
The children, to be precise,
are not here.
确切地讲，不在这里
他们又消失了
They've disappeared again.
That's really careless of you.
卡蒂保姆，你确实太粗心了
That's the third time this week.
这已经是这周的第三次了
The fourth, madam.
第四次，夫人。如果不是气愤之极的话
I've had my fill.
我并不想说他们的坏话
I'm not one to speak
ill of the children.
你估计他们什么时候能回来？
When do you expect them home?
I couldn't say.
If you'd compute my wages...
这可不好说。现在请你算一算我的薪水
Oh, gracious!
You're not leaving?
噢，天，卡蒂保姆！你不是要走吧？ 班克斯先生会怎么说？
What will Mr Banks say?
他回家后，发现孩子们不见了会很生气的
He'll be cross
when he finds the children missing.
艾伦，把这些拿开，你知道这东西会让他多恼火
Put these away.
The cause infuriates Mr Banks.
是的，妇人
I beseech you,
please reconsider.
卡蒂保姆，我请求你，再想一想
Think of the children.
想想孩子们，想想班克斯先生
Think of Mr Banks.
He was just getting used to you.
他刚开始适应你
Posts, everyone!
各就各位！
4, 3, 2, 1...
4，3，2，1，点火！
Fire!
- I do beseech you...
- My wages, if you please.
卡蒂保姆，我请求你…… 我的薪水，请！
今晚早了点，是吗？将军
Bit early tonight, Admiral?
胡说，正点报时，跟往常一样
Nonsense.
Bang on the dot, as usual.
How's the world of finance?
银行里的事情还好吧？
Never better.
从没有比现在更好的时候了，货币坚挺，贷款利率不断上升
Money's sound,
credit rates are moving up,
- and the pound is admired everywhere.
- Good.
英镑成了全世界的宠物
很好 先生，你那儿的情况怎么样？
How about you?
Bit chancy, I'd say.
很难讲
起风了，气压也下降了
The Wind's up.
The glass is falling.
- Don't like it.
- Good. Good, good.
我不喜欢这种情况 好，好，好
Banks, you're steering into
a nasty piece of weather.
班克斯，毫无疑问你将赶上坏天气的
Banks!
班克斯！你听见了么？
Do you hear me?
Hello, Katie Nanna.
That must be heavy. Allow me.
你好，卡蒂保姆。那一定很重吧。
让我来吧
Hmph!
哼！
What a very pretty hat.
多可爱的帽子啊！
I feel a surge of deep satisfaction
就像一位国王
Much as a king astride his noble steed
骑着他的骏马，谢谢
Thank you.
当我摆脱白天的喧嚣，回到家，回到妻子身边
When I return from daily strife
to hearth and wife
我是多么心满意足，我的生活多么愉快！
How pleasant is the life I lead
- Dear, the children...
- Yes, yes, yes.
亲爱的，有件事和孩子们有关 是的，是的，是的
我按照日程表精确地管理着我的家！
I run my home precisely on schedule
At 6:01, I march through my door
6点01分 我走进家门
My slippers, sherry, and pipe
are due at 6:02
6点02分 放下我的手套和手杖
我的生活始终如一！
Consistent is the life I lead
George, they're missing.
乔治，孩子们不见了。 太美妙了。
Splendid, splendid.
It's grand to be an Englishman in 1910
1910年在爱德华国王的统治下
King Edward's on the throne
It's the age of men
做一位英国男人是多么光荣 这是一个男人唯上的时代
我是城堡的主人 统治者
I'm the lord of my castle
The sovereign, the liege
我管理着我的仆人，孩子们和妻子
I treat my subjects
servants, children, wife
严格且温和，贵族的行为理应高尚
With a firm, but gentle hand
Noblesse oblige
It's 6:03, and the heirs to my dominion
are scrubbed and tubbed
现在6点03分，我领地的继承人们
已经洗过了，吃饱了
And adequately fed
我会拍拍他们的头，打发他们去睡觉
And so I'll pat them on the head
and send them off to bed
啊，我的生活多么气派！
Ah, lordly is the life I lead
Winifred, where are the children?
威妮弗蕾德，孩子们在哪儿？ 他们不在这里，亲爱的
They're not here, dear.
什么？他们当然应该在这儿！他们会在别的地方吗？
Of course they're here.
Where else would they be?
我不知道，乔治 你不知道？
- I don't know.
- You don't know?
他们不见了。卡蒂保姆到处都找遍了
They're missing.
Katie Nanna has looked everywhere.
Very well. I'll deal with this at once.
我要立即处理这件事
The police station. Quickly, please.
请给我接警察局，快！
我想这件事不必麻烦警察，事实上……
We needn't bother the police.
The fact is...
Facts cloud the issue.
请别试图用什么事实把事情弄得模糊不清
唯一的事实，很明显，卡蒂保姆不能胜任她的工作
One fact alone is clear.
Katie Nanna's faltered.
She's disappointed us.
I shall bring her to book...
她使得这个家陷入混乱，我要教训教训她……
Oh.
哦，她已经走了，是吗？
- She's left us, hasn't she?
- Yes, only just.
是的，亲爱的，刚刚走
George Banks here.
喂，呃……我是乔治?班克斯
樱桃树大街17号。出了件急事
17 Cherry Tree Lane.
It's a matter of some urgency.
请立即派一名警察
Please send a policeman.
The policeman's here, George.
乔治，警察来了！
什么？噢，真及时！服务真好！
What? Oh. Very prompt.
Wonderful service.
谢谢！晚安
Thank you so much. Good night.
Come in, constable.
请进，警察先生，请进！ 谢谢！
我在公园那边巡逻时
While on duty across the park,
I noted some stray valuables.
发现了两件遗失的贵重物品
- I believe they're yours.
- Valuables?
我相信是你的，先生 贵重物品？
来，过来
Come along now.
简！迈克尔！
Jane.
Michael.
威妮弗蕾德，请别激动
Winifred, don't be emotional.
哦，他们今天走了很多路，精疲力尽了
I wouldn't be too hard on them, sir.
They've had a long, weary walk today.
Children, come here at once.
孩子们，过来
Well?
怎么回事？ 对不起，我们和保姆卡蒂走散了
- Sorry we lost Katie Nanna, Father.
- It was windy...
你知道的，今天风很大，而这个风筝对我们来说大了点
And the kite was too strong.
The kite ran away, sir,
not the children.
在某种意义上说，先生，是风筝跑走了而不是孩子们
Thank you.
I'll manage this.
谢谢，警察先生。我想我能够控制这件事
说实话，这风筝并不好。我们自己做的
It wasn't a good kite.
We made it ourselves.
也许你可以帮我们做一个……
Perhaps if you helped us...
哦，那很重要，先生。风筝很难控制
That's the ticket.
Kites are skittish things.
就在上周，我和我的孩子们……
Only last week...
我非常感谢你送他们回来
I'm very grateful to you, constable.
如果你到厨房看看，厨师会给你弄些吃的
The cook will
find you a plate of something.
谢谢你，先生。我该回去工作了
I shall now return to my duties.
谢谢你，警察先生
Thank you, constable.
Good night, miss. Good night, ma'am.
Good night, sir.
晚安，小姐。晚安，夫人，晚安，先生
"Cook will find something."
厨师会给我弄些吃的。我从没……
乔治，我非常非常抱歉
I'm awfully sorry about this, George.
You'll want to discuss it.
我猜你大概要谈谈这件事
I would, indeed.
的确！
艾伦，带简和迈克尔到楼上去
Ellen, take the children upstairs.
Yes, sir.
好的，先生
我就知道。谁首当其冲的负担这一切？
I knew it.
Who bears the brunt of everything?
我！就是这样！
Me, that's who.
They don't want
an honest working girl here.
他们不想要一个诚实勤劳的人
他们需要的是动物园看守
They need a ruddy zoo keeper.
Sorry.
我很抱歉，亲爱的。我当初之所以选中了卡蒂保姆……
When I chose Katie Nanna,
I thought she'd be firm.
是因为她看上去那么严厉
She looked solemn, cross.
她看上去会严格地要求孩子们。
威妮弗蕾德，不要把效率和急躁混为一谈
Never confuse efficiency
with a liver complaint.
下次我会试着干得好一点
I'll do better next time.
Next time? You've engaged six nannies.
They've all been unqualified disasters.
下次？亲爱的，过去的四个月里你已经换了六个保姆
个个都是不称职的灾星 我同意
I quite agree.
给孩子们选保姆是一项重要而细致的任务
Choosing a nanny is a delicate task,
requiring insight, balanced judgment,
and an ability to read character.
它要求深入的观察，公正的判断，还有识别人的能力
Under the circumstances,
在这种情况下，只好由我亲自来……
it might be apropos
to select the next person myself.
呃，处理了
Would you, George?
噢，乔治？！ 显然想要选出一位合适的保姆
I'll do this properly.
就应该采用恰当的方式
I'll advertise in The Times.
我要在《泰晤士报》上登一则广告。请你记下来
- Take this down, please.
- Yes, of course.
当然，是的，亲爱的。 招聘
Wanted... No, required...
呃，不，呃，要求一位……
Nanny.
严厉、受人尊敬言谈稳重的保姆
Firm, respectable, no-nonsense.
A British nanny must be a general
以为英国的保姆应该像一位将军
The future empire lies within her hands
帝国的未来就掌握在她的手中
And so the person that we need
to mould the breed
因此我们需要塑造孩童的人
应该是一位能够发号施令的保姆
It is a nanny who can give commands
你记下来了么，威妮弗蕾德？ 噢，是的，亲爱的，一字不差
- Getting this, Winifred?
- Yes, every word.
A British bank is run with precision
一家英国银行的运作在准确无误的基础上
A British home requires nothing less
一个英国家庭也要求丝毫不差
Tradition, discipline, and rules
must be the tools
传统，纪律和规则是我们的工具
Without them
disorder, catastrophe, anarchy
失去了这些，将陷入混乱，灾难，无政府状态
In short, you have a ghastly mess
总之，可怕的混乱
Splendid, George. Inspirational.
The Times will be so pleased.
精辟，乔治！很有启迪
《泰晤士报》会很满意的
- Father.
- Yes?
父亲？ 什么？
我们已经商量过了
We've discussed everything,
and we're very sorry about today.
对今天的所做作为，我们感到非常抱歉
I should think so.
我想应该是的
- It was wrong.
- Indeed.
从卡蒂保姆那里跑走是不应该的 是这样
We'll cooperate with the new nanny.
我们这么干的目的就是想要换一位新的保姆
I'll be glad for your help.
很明智。我很高兴在这件事上能得到你们的帮助
That's why we wrote this advertisement.
我们认为你会同意的。所以我们写了一份广告
Advertisement for what?
什么广告 招聘新保姆的
The new nanny.
- You wrote an...
- George, let's listen.
你们写了一份广告…… 乔治，我想我们应该听一听
You wanted our help.
你说过你需要我们的帮助 但我是……哦，好吧
Oh, very well.
为两位极其可爱的孩子招聘一个保姆
"Wanted, a nanny for
two adorable children."
及其可爱的？应该说是“极其难管”的
"Adorable."
That's debatable, I must say.
如果你想得到这个职位
"If you want this choice position
你应该开朗活泼
"Have a cheery disposition"
Jane, I don't...
简，我不是…… 面庞红润，没有疣子
"Rosy cheeks, no warts
那是我加进去的 精通各种游戏
I wrote that.
"Play games, all sorts
"You must be kind
你必须善良和蔼，聪明机智
"You must be witty
恬美可爱，且美丽漂亮
"Very sweet and fairly pretty“
- That's. ..
- George, please.
好了，简直荒唐透顶…… 乔治，别这样！
带我们出游 款待我们
"Take us on outings, give us treats
为我们唱歌 还要带上甜点
"Sing songs, bring sweets
"Never be cross or cruel
从不发火
绝不拿蓖麻油和薄粥糊弄我们
"Never give us castor oil or gruel
"Love us as a son and daughter
爱我们如同自己的子女
还有不能有大麦茶味儿
"And never smell of barley water"
这条也是我加进去的
I wrote that, too.
"If you won't scold and dominate us
如果你不斥责我们，压制我们
我们绝不会做让你恨我们的事情
"We will never give you
cause to hate us
"We won't hide your spectacles
so you can't see
我们不会藏起你的眼镜，让你找不到
"Put toads in your bed
or pepper in your tea
把青蛙放在你的床上，或把胡椒粉倒进你的茶里
好保姆，快点来
"Hurry, nanny
"Many thanks
此致……敬礼
“Sincerely
"Jane and Michael Banks"
简和迈克尔?班克斯敬上
谢谢。非常有趣
Thank you. Most interesting.
We've had enough of this.
现在我听够了你们的胡言乱语
Please return to the nursery.
回房间去吧
他们毕竟是个小孩子，他们只是想帮帮忙
- They were only trying to help.
- I'm aware of that.
我知道他们还是小孩子
I congratulate myself on stepping in.
我很庆幸我决定介入这件事情
"Play games, sing songs, give treats."
Ridiculous.
“游戏，唱歌，甜点”
荒唐！毫无疑问
No question in my mind.
Now is the time for action.
该开始行动了
The Times, please.
请告诉我《泰晤士报》的号码 不，我当然不知道号码
I don't know the number.
Oh, George, you're always so forceful.
哦，乔治，你总是这么强势
泰晤士报？我是乔治?班克斯
The Times?
George Banks, Cherry Tree Lane.
樱桃树大街17号。我要在你们的栏目上登一则广告
I wish to place an advertisement.
- Time gun ready?
- Ready and charged, sir.
报时枪准备好了么？ 准备完毕，将军！
I'll take the report, Mr Binnacle.
请报告，宾纳克先生
是。风向已经转变，好像来自一个新的区域
Wind's coming from a new quarter.
So it is.
是的 先生？ 什么事？
- Sir.
- What?
左舷船首好像出事了
Something taking place
off the port bow.
Ghastly looking crew, I must say.
我不得不说，一群可怕的人
There's a queue of nannies outside.
Shall I show them in'?
门外的保姆排起了长队，先生。能让她们进来了么？
艾伦，我说过了8点钟开始，就8点
I said 8:00, and 8:00 it shall be.
12 seconds to go.
还有12秒
- 10, 9...
- Posts!
10，9，8…… 各就各位！
7, 6, 5, 4.
7，6，5，4……
3，2，1！
3,2,1.
艾伦，现在8点整了
it is now 8:00.
Yes, sir.
是的，先生
I have told you repeatedly, Ellen,
艾伦，我已经告诉你多遍……
我不喜欢做事没有条理
I dislike being hurried into things.
I don't understand.
我不明白，他们一点也不符合咱们的广告
They're nothing like
what we advertised for.
Woof! Woof! Woof!
Michael, look!
迈克尔，看！
不会是一个巫婆吧。
- Perhaps it's a witch.
- Nonsense. Witches have brooms.
当然不是，巫婆都是骑着扫把
It's her. It's the person.
She's answered our advertisement.
就是她，咱们想要的人。她看了我们的广告
她符合咱们的每一个条件
Rosy cheeks and everything.
- Show them in, one at a time.
- Yes, sir.
艾伦，你可以把她们带进来了，一次一个
是的，先生
你请进，每次一位 谢谢
- Come in, one at a time.
- Thank you.
哦
You are the father of
Jane and Michael Banks?
你就是简和迈克尔的父亲吗？
I said, you are the father of
Jane and Michael Banks?
我说，你是简和迈克尔的父亲吗？
Yes, of course.
噢，是的，当然
You brought your references?
你带了推荐信吧？我可以看看吗？
I never give references.
哦，我的原则是不提供推荐信
I believe it very old-fashioned.
依我看，那已经过时了
We'll see about that then.
是么？我们还是有必要看一看
Now then, the qualifications.
现在，看看广告上的要求吧
Item one, "A cheery disposition."
第一条：开朗活泼
我从不生气
I am never cross.
Item two, "Rosy cheeks."
第二条：面庞红润
Obviously.
显而易见
Item three, "Play games, all sorts."
第三条：会做各种游戏
They'll find my games
extremely diverting.
我可以肯定孩子们会发现我的游戏花样繁多
Where did you get this paper?
I tore it up.
这张纸，你从哪里弄到的？我记得我已经把它撕了
Excuse me.
抱歉，第四条：必须善良和蔼
Item four, "You must be kind."
I am kind, but extremely firm.
我很善良，但非常严格
Have you lost something?
你丢了什么东西吗？ 啊！是
That paper. I thought that I...
那张纸，我想我……
You are George Banks?
你是乔治?班克斯先生吗？ 什么？
And you did advertise for a nanny?
你登了广告招聘保姆，是吗？
George Banks.
乔治?班克斯 那就好
Very well, then.
Tore it up, turned it over,
threw it in the...
我撕了它，转过来
又撕了一下，然后扔在哪儿
请原谅，你生病了吗？
Are you ill?
I hope not.
我希望没有
About my wages...
现在谈谈我的薪水吧。关于这一点这上面很模糊
- The reference is obscure.
- Obscure.
是很模糊 我们有必要明确下来
We must be clear on that.
的确有必要 每隔一个星期二我得休息一天
- I require every second Tuesday off.
- Every Tuesday.
每个星期二
Perhaps a trial period would be wise.
另外，规定一个试用期也许是明智的做法
Hmm... I'll give you one week.
I'll know by then.
我给你一个星期的时间
I'll see the children now.
我去看看孩子们，谢谢你
Close your mouth. We are not codfish.
迈克尔，把你的嘴闭上，我们不是鳕鱼
Don't stand there. Best foot forward.
别光站在那儿看，走吧
Spit Spot.
动作快点
- George?
- Aah!
乔治？ 哈？
乔治，你到底在做什么？
I thought you were
interviewing nannies.
我还以为你正在面试那些保姆呢 刚才还是！
I was, I was.
你是说你已经选完了？
You've selected one already?
Yes, it's done.
是的，都结束了。 那么，她在哪儿？
- Where is she?
- In the nursery.
什么？她在孩子们的房间里
我的意思是让她开始工作了。 你太英明了
- I put her to work straight-away.
- How clever.
I'd have muddled everything.
要是我一定会把事情搞砸的
Is she everything
that we hoped she'd be?
告诉我，她是不是符合我们的所有要求？
It all happened rather quickly.
I mean, I... I, uh...
一切都发生得太快了，我的意思是……
她严厉吗？她会发号施令吗？
Will she be firm and give commands?
Will she mould our young breed?
她能塑造孩子们吗？
我想她能
Winifred, I think she will.
I think she will!
那么，也许最好让艾伦
In that case, perhaps
Ellen should dismiss the others.
告诉其他的人可以走了
The others?
其他人？哦，是的，艾伦？ 是的，先生？
- Ellen!
- Yes, sir?
Tell the others
the position's been filled.
告诉其他人可以走了，这位置已经有了合适的人选
- The others, sir?
- Yes, the others.
其他人？ 是的，其他人。
How many nannies
does this house need?
她以为我们需要几个保姆
The position has been filled.
这个位置已经有了合适的人选
I'm afraid the nursery isn't very tidy.
恐怕我们的房间不够整洁
Rather like a bear pit.
就像一个大熊的窝，对吗？
- That's a funny bag.
- Carpet.
你的包真滑稽 是地毯
- To carry carpets?
- No, made of.
你是说包里装的是地毯吗？ 不，是用地毯做的
这是你的房间，从这里可以欣赏到公园
Your room has a lovely view.
Hmm...
嗯
好吧，毕竟不是白金汉宫
It's not exactly Buckingham Palace...
Still, it's clean.
还挺干净
Yes, it will be quite suitable.
我觉得它很合适
只是到处需要整理一下
Just needs a touch here and there.
First things first.
首先，就像我常说的那样
The place to hang a hat
is on a hat stand.
挂帽子最合适的地方就是衣帽架
Oh!
哈！这怎么能用呢？
This will never do.
I much prefer
seeing all of my face at once.
我更喜欢大一点的
But there was nothing in it.
但是里面是空的呀！
Never judge things
by their appearance, even carpetbags.
不要根据表面现象作判断
即使是一只地毯包。我就从来没有
I never do.
"A thing of beauty is a joy forever."
美丽的东西永远是快乐的
Hmm... A little more light perhaps.
嗯，也许应该更亮一些
We'd better watch this one.
我们最好多留心这家伙
- She's tricky.
- She's wonderful.
她很狡猾。 她棒极了。
Much better.
这下好多了！
Now, let me see.
我瞧瞧
That's funny. I always carry it.
It must be here somewhere.
奇怪，我总是随身带着的。一定放在什么地方了
- What?
- My tape measure.
什么东西？ 类型测量尺
- What for?
- To see how you measure up.
你找它来干什么？ 我想知道你们俩个属于哪一类。
That's the funniest thing I ever saw.
这是我见过的最好笑的事情。我知道它就在里面的某个地方
Ah ha ha ha. Here it is.
啊，哈哈，找到了
Good.
好，过来，快一点！
Come along, then. Quickly.
Head up, Michael. Don't slouch.
抬起头来，迈克尔。别无精打采的。
Just as I thought.
"Extremely stubborn and suspicious."
跟我想的一样“非常倔强，多疑”
- I am not.
- See for yourself.
我没有！ 自己看
极其顽固，且多……
- "Extremely stubborn and susips..."
- Suspicious.
多疑！
Now you, Jane.
轮到你了，简
嗯，“爱傻笑，不把东西放好”
"Rather inclined to giggle.
Doesn't put things away."
How about you?
那么你呢？
Very well. Hold this for me.
我们来看看吧，拿着！
As I expected.
正如我所预料的，“玛丽?泼平斯”
"Mary Poppins,
practically perfect in every way."
“一切都近乎完美”
Mary Poppins.
Is that your name? It's lovely.
玛丽?泼平斯！这是你的名字吗？真可爱
谢谢。我也一直很喜欢它
I've always liked it.
Shall we move?
现在，我们可以开始了吧？ 开始什么？
In your advertisement,
did you not request games?
在广告里，你不是特别提到了会做各种游戏吗？
Yes.
哦，是的！ 很好，那么……
First we'll play
"Well Begun ls Half Done."
我们的第一个游戏就叫做“好的开始是成功的一半”
That sounds suspicious.
我不喜欢，听上去不太好
Otherwise entitled,
"Let's Tidy Up The Nursery."
换个名字就叫“让我们开始整理房间”
I told you she was tricky.
我告诉过你她很狡猾
Shall we begin?
我们可以开始了么？ 玛丽?泼平斯，你认为这是个游戏么？
It is a game, isn't it?
Depends on your viewpoint.
这取决于你如何看待它
You see, in every job that must be
clone, there is an element of fun.
你要知道，在每一件我们必须要完成的工作里
都蕴含着快乐的成分
你要发现快乐，抓住它！
You find the fun,
and snap, the job's a game.
工作就变成了游戏
And every task you undertake
你承担的每一项任务都变得轻松
becomes a piece of cake
A lark, a spree
愉快，充满了乐趣
It's very clear to see
显而易见
That a
一汤匙糖可以
spoonful of sugar
helps the medicine go down
帮助你把药喝下去
甜药好入口
The medicine go down
Medicine go down
只要一汤匙糖就能帮助你把药喝下去
Just a spoonful of sugar
helps the medicine go down
In a most delightful way
让人意犹未尽
A robin feathering his nest
has very little time to rest
正在筑巢的知更鸟，没有空闲去休息
While gathering
his bits of twine and twig
它要一点一点地收集筑巢的材料
Though quite intent in his pursuit
He has a merry tune to toot
尽管它那样执着于工作，但它仍然唱着快乐的歌
He knows a song
因为他知道，歌声会使工作变得轻松愉快
Will move the job along
For a spoonful of sugar
helps the medicine go down
因为一汤匙糖能帮助你把药喝下去
甜药好入口
The medicine go down
Medicine go down
Just a spoonful of sugar
helps the medicine go down
只要一汤匙糖能帮助你把药喝下去
In a most delightful way
让人意犹未尽
The honeybees that fetch the nectar
from the ?owers to the comb
蜜蜂采集花蜜
Never tire of ever buzzing to and fro
嗡嗡嗡，飞来飞去，从不厌倦
Because they take a little nip
from every ?ower that they sip
因为它们从采过的每一朵花里只汲取了一点点
And hence
因此…… 因此……
They find
它们发现…… 它们发现……
Their task is not a grind
它们的任务不再沉重
Aaah
Cheeky.
真无耻
Don't be all day.
别没完没了得了
Let me out! Let me out!
放我出去！
Let me out!
Well...
好了！非常……
Thank you now.
非常感谢……
When you've quite finished!
现在，你应该结束了！
Thank you.
谢谢！
That's quite sufficient.
到此为止吧。请拿上你们的外套和帽子
Hats and coats, please.
It's time for our outing.
接下来，我们去公园
Let's tidy up the nursery again.
我不想出去，我还想整理房间
Enough's as good as a feast.
适可而止是最好不过的了，请跟上来
You're not as well
turned out as I'd like.
让我瞧瞧，你这样子还不够好
幸好，还有时间
Still, there's time.
Spit Spot.
动作快点！出发
And off we go!
For a spoonful of sugar
helps the medicine go down
因为一汤匙糖能帮助你把药喝下去
The medicine go down
Medicine go down
甜药好入口
Just a spoonful of sugar
helps the medicine go down
只要一汤匙糖能帮助你把药喝下去
In the most delightful way
让人意犹未尽
Chim chiminy chim chiminy
Chim chim cheroo
黑烟囱……冒黑烟……
我做我喜欢的事情，我喜欢……
I does what I likes and I likes...
What I do
我做的事情
Hello, art lovers.
你好，热爱艺术的人！
Today I'm a screever
正如你所看到的，今天我是个马路画家
And as you can see
A screever's an artist
马路画家是最高水平的艺术家
Of highest degree
And it's all me own work
from me own memory
这是我记忆中所有的作品
Not Royal Academy.
Still, they're not bad, are they?
虽然不是出于英国皇家艺术院
但是看上去还是非常不错的吧？
Chim chiminy chim chiminy
Chim chim cheroo
黑烟囱……冒黑烟
I draws what I likes
and I likes what I drew
我画我喜欢的，我喜欢我画的
No remuneration do I ask of you
我不索取任何报酬
But me cap would be glad
of a copper or two
但我的帽子很欢迎
Me cap would be glad
of a copper or two
一两个铜板
Wait!
等等！别动
Don't move.
Don't move a muscle.
千万别动
Stay right where you are.
就呆在那儿！
I'd know that silhouette anywhere.
我就知道！玛丽?泼平斯！
- Mary Poppins!
- Hello, Bert.
很高兴再见到你，伯特。这是简和迈克尔
You know Jane and Michael.
Well, I've seen them here and about.
Chasing a kite last time, weren't it?
我上次看见他们，正在追一只风筝，对吧？
We're going to the park.
玛丽?泼平斯要带我们去公园
To the park?
去公园？我知道玛丽?泼平斯是不会的
Not if I know Mary Poppins.
Other nannies go to the park.
别的保姆会带孩子们去公园，但是……
When you're with Mary Poppins,
你们现在是和玛丽?泼平斯在一起，一下子你们就到了连做梦都想不到的地方
quick as you can say,
"Bob's your uncle,"
迅速到你都还没察觉
the most unusual things happen.
最不寻常的事情就开始了
What are you talking about?
你再说什么，我一点也不知道
好吧，你知道我本来不应该说的，但是……
It's not my place to say,
but she probably has in mind
a jolly holiday.
她脑子里有一个令人兴奋的好地方
Something along these lines.
沿着这些线就能到哪儿，对此我是不应感到惊讶的
“在泰晤士河上泛舟”如果你们喜欢出游，那绝对是个好去处
That's always good. Here we go.
我们到了
How about a lovely circus?
Lions and tigers.
马戏团。去看看可爱的马戏团如何？有狮子和老虎
World famous artistes
举世闻名的杂技演员为你……
performing death-defying feats
of dexterity and skill.
表演精彩绝伦的节目
Ta-da!
Oh, that's lovely.
I'd much rather go there.
哦，那太可爱了。如果你愿意的话，我更想去那儿！
A typical English countryside
done by a loving hand.
很美，是吗？典型的英国乡村景象……
好像出自一位真正的乡村爱好者之手
Though you can't see it, there's
a little country fair down that road.
沿着这条路走下去，翻过这座山……
有一个乡村集市，不过你现在看不见
I don't see any road.
这儿根本就没有路
What? No road?
什么？没有路？
只要在这儿添点东西就行了……
Just wants a bit of something here
and a bit of something there.
还有那儿
好了，一条乡村小路很适合旅行和探险
There.
A country road
suitable for travel and high adventure.
请让我们去吧，玛丽?泼平斯
May we go, Mary Poppins, please?
Don't you think it's lovely,
Mary Poppins?
多可爱的地方啊！你不觉得它很可爱吗？
Now's the time. No one's looking.
现在正是时候，玛丽?泼平斯。没人注意
Oh, please. Please.
求求你了，玛丽?泼平斯！
我可不愿意出自己的丑，谢谢了
I have no intention of making
a spectacle of myself.
好吧，我自己来
All right. I'll do it myself.
Do what?
你要干什么？ 变个小魔法
Bit of magic.
魔法？ 是的，很容易
- Magic?
- It's easy.
Let's see.
让我来看看。你头脑里想着
You think.
You wink.
眨一下眼睛
You do a double blink.
眨两下
You close your eyes and jump.
闭上眼，跳！
Is something supposed to happen?
什么都没发生啊
Bert, what utter nonsense.
伯特，别胡闹了！
Oh.
Why do you complicate things?
你为什么总是把很简单的事情弄复杂了
Give me your hand, Michael.
Don't slouch.
把手给我，迈克尔。抬起头
1, 2...
1，2
Mary Poppins, you look beautiful.
玛丽?泼平斯，你看上去真漂亮
- Do you really think so?
- Cross my heart, you do.
你真的这样认为吗？ 凭良心说，确实是。就像我初次见到你的时候一样
You look fine, too, Bert.
你也很棒，伯特
Isn't there a fair?
我记得你说过那儿有一个集市
Down the road and behind the hill.
是的，沿着这条路往前，山后就是，记住了吗？
快来！我听到了旋转木马的声音
I hear the merry-go-round.
- Tell them hello.
- Don't smudge the drawing.
告诉他们是伯特让你们去的 别摔了，弄脏了画！
Ain't it a glorious day
Right as a mornin' in May
多么美妙的一天
就在这五月的早晨
I feel like I could ?y
我想要飞翔
Now, Bert, none of your larking about.
别闹了，伯特
Have you ever seen
the grass so green
你见过这么嫩绿的草地吗
Or a bluer sky
或比这更湛蓝的天空吗？
噢，跟玛丽在一起就是一个快乐的假日
Oh, it's a jolly holiday with Mary
Mary makes your heart so light
玛丽让你的心变得轻松 你一点都没有变，是吧？
You haven't changed.
When the day is grey and ordinary
灰暗阴沉的日子里
Mary makes the sun shine bright
玛丽让它阳光明媚 噢，的确
Oh, honestly.
Oh, happiness is bloomin'
all around her
幸福在她的周围荡漾
The daffodils are smiling at the dove
洋水仙正对着小鸽子微笑
When Mary holds your hand
You feel so grand
当玛丽牵着你的手，你感到无比的骄傲
Your heart starts beatin'
like a big brass band
你的心跳动比得上一个军乐队
You are light-headed.
你有点头晕脑涨了 和玛丽在一起是一个快乐的节日
It's a jolly holiday with Mary
No wonder that it's Mary that we love
毫无疑问，玛丽是我们的钟爱
Oh, it's a jolly holiday with Mary
和玛丽在一起就是一个快乐的节日
Mary makes your heart so light
玛丽让你的心轻松
When the day is grey and ordinary
灰暗阴沉的日子里
玛丽让它阳光明媚
Mary makes the sun shine bright
Oh, happiness is bloomin'
all around her
幸福在她的周围荡漾
The daffodils are smiling
at the dove, oink, oink
洋水仙正对着小鸽子微笑
When Mary holds your hand
You feel so grand
当玛丽牵着你的手，你感到无比的骄傲
Your heart starts beatin'
like a big brass band
你的心跳动比得上一个军乐队
It's a jolly holiday with Mary
和玛丽在一起是一个快乐的节日
No wonder that it's Mary that we love
毫无疑问，玛丽是我们的钟爱
Thank you.
谢谢 非常荣幸，玛丽?泼平斯
Our pleasure, Mary Poppins.
Oh, it's a jolly holiday with you, Bert
伯特，和你在一起就是一个快乐的节日
Gentlemen like you are few
像你这样的绅士少而又少 正在消失
A vanishing breed.
Though you're just
a diamond in the rough, Bert
你是裹在破旧衣裳里的钻石
Underneath your blood is blue
你的血统是高贵的 这谁都知道
Common knowledge.
You'd never think
of pressing your advantage
你从不炫耀
Forbearance
is the hallmark of your creed
克制是你的原则 是的
A lady needn't fear
when you are near
有你的陪伴，女士不再恐惧
Your sweet gentility is crystal clear
你的温柔甜蜜 彬彬有礼
Oh, it's a jolly holiday with you, Bert
伯特，和你在一起就是一个快乐的节日
A jolly, jolly holiday with you
一个快乐幸福的节日
服务生！
Waiter! Waiter?
来点什么呢？
Now then, what would be nice?
先来一份冰镇山莓
We'll start with raspberry ice
And then some cakes and tea
再来些糕点和茶
Order what you will
您不再点些别的吗？ 我们这儿不收费
There'll be no bill
It's complimentary
免费赠送
You're very kind.
你们真是太好了
Anything for you, Mary Poppins.
愿意为你效劳，玛丽?泼平斯
You're our favourite person.
你是受欢迎的人
Right you are.
你说对了，梅维斯和希尔比常有办法取胜
It's true that...
Mavis and Sybil
have ways that are winning
普鲁登斯和格温多林能让你激动不已
And Prudence and Gwendolyn
set your heart spinnin'
Phoebe's delightful
Maude is disarming
菲比总是高高兴兴，莫德很善解人意
Felicia, Janice and Lydia
珍妮丝，费利西娅和莉迪亚很可爱
Charming!
Cynthia's dashing, Vivian's sweet
辛西娅很迷人，维维安很甜美，斯蒂芬妮很了不起，普里西拉很好客
Stephanie's smashing, Priscilla a treat
Veronica, Millicent, Agnes, and Jane
韦洛尼加，米莉森特，艾格尼丝和简
Convivial company, time and again
是一些乐观的好伙伴，再来一遍
Dorcas and Phyllis and Glynis are sorts
I'll agree are three jolly good sports
道克斯，菲利斯和格林尼斯是运动员
我同意他们是三个最出色的运动员
But cream of the crop, tip of the top
is Mary Poppins and there we stop
但，最优秀最出类拔萃的是……
是玛丽?泼平斯 就到这里
When Mary holds your hand
You feel so grand
当玛丽牵着你的手，你感到无比的骄傲
Your heart starts beatin'
like a big brass band
你的心跳动比得上一个军乐队
Woo!
It's a jolly holiday with Mary
和玛丽在一起是一个快乐的节日
No wonder that it's Mary that we love
毫无疑问玛丽是我们的钟爱
Yahoo!
Yahoo! Yahoo!
Our own private merry-go-round.
我们私人的旋转木马
Nice. Very nice, indeed,
很好，事实上……
if you don't want to go nowhere.
如果你们不想去其他的地方
谁说我们不打算去其他地方？
Who says we're not going anywhere?
Oh, guard!
管理员！
Righto. Mary Poppins.
好的，玛丽?泼平斯
Thank you.
谢谢
They're off!
他们走了！玛丽?泼平斯领先两马身
Mary Poppins leads by two lengths,
Jane's second by...
简领先一马身，迈克尔第三
My horse is the fastest.
我的马跑得最快
伙计，你听到了么？你甘心落后吗？
Hear that, mate?
Want to put up with that?
来吧，咱们比赛一下。女士。这是你最快的速度吗？
Is that the best you can do?
Hurry up, boy!
加油，加油！
Not so fast, please. Michael.
别跑那么快，迈克尔！
Bert, you're just as bad.
伯特，你真淘气，像个孩子
Sorry. Whoa, boy. Whoa.
对不起，慢点，慢点
慢点
Easy, boy. Whoa. Whoa.
Just a bit of high spirits,
Mary Poppins.
这可真是趟奇特的旅行
Please control yourself.
We're not on a racecourse.
请你控制一下自己。咱们不是在赛马场上
Follow me, please.
请跟我来
- Good morning.
- Oh, yes, quite. What?
早上好 好……呃？怎么回事……
I say.
我说！
Have you...
你有没有
Ever?
Never!
从没有！
View halloo.
发现狐狸！
Oh, yes, definitely. A view halloo.
哦，是的，绝对，发现狐狸了
View halloo?
发现狐狸？
Faith and Begorra.
'Tis them redcoats again.
天！又是那些英国兵！
发现狐狸！
Oh, musha, musha.
Poor little bloke.
可怜的家伙，让我来帮你一把吧
Let's give him a hand.
Saints preserve us.
圣人啊，保佑我们！
Yikes!
呀！
Tally ho!
Da-doo da-doo!
跑啊！
Up you go. Now hang on.
你上来吧，抓好了！
Would you look at this?
An elegant merry-go-round horse.
你看清楚了么？这可是了不起的旋转木马
Come on, you dirty omadhauns.
I'll lick all of you.
过来比试比试呀，你们这帮坏蛋
我能揍扁你们
Faster, me beauty.
Faster!
快点，美人，快点！
Riders, would you be kind
and let me pass?
噢！骑手们，我可以先行一步吗？
Certainly, ma'am.
当然可以，夫人
- Thank you.
- Not at all, ma'am.
谢谢 不客气，夫人
Excellent time, gentlemen.
非常好的成绩，先生们
- Quite.
- Perfect day for it.
哦，是的，非常好 完美的成绩，当然
Ahem.
多漂亮啊
Oh, how nice.
Hooray! Yay! Yay!
万岁！万岁！
Hold still.
Watch the dickie bird.
现在别动，看镜头
- How does it feel to win?
- Well...
玛丽?泼平斯，请你谈谈取得胜利后的感受
好的，我…… 赢得了巨大的财富和荣誉吧？
- Gaining fame and fortune.
- Yes.
是的 可以将你的照片刊登在报纸上吗？
- Your picture in the newspaper.
- Actually...
当然，我很愿意
Extreme good looks, may I say?
除了你精彩的照片外，你能说几句话描述一下你的心情吗？
好的，我…… 有没有一个词能形容你此刻的心情
No words describe your emotion?
Gentlemen, on the contrary,
there's a very good word.
先生们，先生们，很抱歉
不过有一个非常好的词
- Right?
- Tell them.
对吧，伯特？ 告诉他们是什么吧
Right.
好的
It's supercalifragilisticexpialidocious
那就是“超级霹雳快乐的不得了”
Even though the sound of it
is something quite atrocious
尽管听起来很糟糕
If you say it loud enough
You'll always sound precocious
但是如果你大声地说出来，听起来就好像你很博学
Supercalifragilisticexpialidocious
超级霹雳快乐的不得了
Um diddle diddle diddle
um diddle ay
当我还是一个小男孩的时候，我很害怕说话
'Cause I was afraid to speak
when I was just a lad
Me father gave me nose a tweak
and told me I was bad
我父亲拧着我的鼻子说我太差劲了
But then one day I learnt a word
that saved me aching nose
但有一天我学会了一个词，它救了我的鼻子
The biggest word you ever heard
and this is how it goes
你听过的最长的一个词
超级霹雳快乐的不得了
Oh, supercalifragilisticexpialidocious
Even though the sound of it
is something quite atrocious
尽管听起来很糟糕
If you say it loud enough
You'll always sound precocious
但是如果你大声地说出来，听起来就好像你很博学
Supercalifragilisticexpialidocious
超级霹雳快乐的不得了
Um diddle diddle diddle
um diddle ay
He travelled all around the world
And everywhere he went
他周游世界
He'd use his word and all would say,
"There goes a clever gent"
每到一处他就用这个词，人们都说她很聪明
When dukes and maharajas
pass the time of day with me
我和罗马的公爵，印度的邦主一起消遣
I say me special word
and then they ask me out to tea
我说这个奇怪的词，他们便请我喝茶
Supercalifragilisticexpialidocious
超级霹雳快乐的不得了
Even though the sound of it
is something quite atrocious
尽管听起来很糟糕
If you say it loud enough
You'll always sound precocious
但是如果你大声地说出来，听起来就好像你很博学
Supercalifragilisticexpialidocious
超级霹雳快乐的不得了
Um diddle diddle diddle um diddle ay
You can say it backwards...
Dociousaliexpiistifragicalirupes.
你知道，你也可以倒过来说……
了得不的乐快雳霹级超
- Bit too much?
- Indubitably.
但你不认为这样太长了点吗？ 毫无疑问
So when the cat has got your tongue
There's no need for dismay
所以当你实在无话可说的时候，没有必要沮丧
Just summon up this word
and then you've got a lot to say
就想想这个词吧，然后你会有很多话要说
But better use it carefully
or it could change your life
不过，要小心用好它，因为它会改变你的生活
For example, I said it to me girl.
比如说？ 怎样？
一天晚上，我对一个女孩说起它，这个女孩就成了我的妻子
Now me girl's me wife.
她还是那么可爱
And a lovely thing she is.
She's supercalifragilisticexpialidocious
那就是，超级霹雳快乐的不得了
Supercalifragilisticexpialidocious
超级霹雳快乐的不得了
Jane, Michael!
简！迈克尔！
Stay close now.
靠近些
Oh, Bert, all your fine drawings.
哦，伯特，可惜你那些美丽的画
There's more where they came from.
没关系，它的出处还有好多
Meantime, I'm changing businesses.
This is hot chestnut weather.
再说，我就要改行了，这鬼天气，真能热死人
Come along, children.
来吧，孩子们 再见，伯特
- Bye, Bert.
- Bye-bye.
再见
- Bye.
- Bye, Jane and Michael.
再见，简和迈克尔
Chim chiminy, chim chiminy
Chim chim cheroo
黑烟囱……冒黑烟……
La dum da da dum
Da da da da dum
No, I won't take your nasty medicine!
不，不，我不想吃你这讨厌的药。
Do we have to, Mary Poppins?
必须得吃么，玛丽?泼平斯？
People with wet feet
must take their medicine.
弄湿脚的人就必须得吃药
I don't want it.
我不想吃，我真不想……
Oh!
Lime cordial! Delicious!
酸橙汁！味道好极了！
Strawberry! Mmm!
草莓汁！
Rum punch.
朗姆酒
Quite satisfactory.
真可口
You won't ever leave us, will you?
玛丽?泼平斯，你永远都不会离开我们的，是吗？
Do you have a handkerchief?
你的枕头底下有没有手帕？ 嗯
Will you stay if we're good?
如果我们发誓做一个乖孩子，你会留下来吗？
A pie crust promise.
Easily made, easily broken.
阿呃！那是一个脆弱的诺言。轻易地许下，轻易地违背
Whatever would we do without you?
没有了你，我们该怎么办？
I'll stay until the wind changes.
我将呆到风向改变了为止
How long will that be?
但是，玛丽?泼平斯，那会多长时间呢？
It's time to go to sleep.
请安静些，你们该睡觉了
We couldn't possibly go to sleep.
So many lovely things happened today!
哦，我们根本睡不着。今天遇到了那么多有趣的事情
Did they?
有吗？ 是啊！当我们跳进伯特的粉笔画里
We jumped into Bert's picture.
The horses fled the carousel.
我们骑着旋转木马，突然所有的木马都一跃而起
And we went riding!
我们飞驰在原野上
Tally ho! Tchunga!
Tally ho! Yoicks!
真的吗？
Really?
Don't you remember?
You won the race.
玛丽?泼平斯，你都不记得了吗？你还得了赛马冠军
A respectable person like me?
How dare you.
一个像我这样受尊重的人出现在赛马会上？你们怎么敢暗示这样的事
I saw you do it.
但是我看见了，是你！
Another word
and I'll summon a policeman.
别说了，否则，我就要叫警察了！明白吗？
I saw it happen!
确实是这样的！我看见了！
- Go to sleep.
- I don't want to.
去睡觉吧 不，我不想睡
We're much too excited.
玛丽?泼平斯，我们太兴奋了！
Very well. Suit yourselves.
好吧，随你们的便
Stay awake
保持清醒
Don't rest your head
别放松你的脑子
Don't lie down
别躺在
Upon your bed
你的床上
While the moon
当月亮漫步在……
Drifts in the skies
夜空的时候
Stay awake
别睡着了
Don't close
不要合上你的眼睛
Your eyes
Though the world
虽然整个世界都已入睡
ls fast asleep
Though your pillow's
虽然你的枕头柔软舒适
Soft and deep
You're not sleepy
你并没有昏昏欲睡
As you seem
Stay awake
别睡着
Don't nod and dream
别打盹
别做梦
Stay awake
别睡着
Don't nod
别打盹
And dream
别做梦
Glorious day, Mr Binnacle, glorious.
今天天气很好，宾纳克先生。
Nobody sleeps this morning.
Put in double powder.
今早不会再有人睡懒觉了，装双倍的火药
A double charge?
Aye, sir.
双倍的火药？是，将军！
Shake things up a bit, what?
会震得更厉害，是吗？
- Lovely, lovely morning, Ellen.
- Indeed it is, ma'am.
多可爱的早晨啊，艾伦 的确是，夫人
- You packed the spoiled eggs?
- Yes.
你把那些臭鸡蛋放到我的包里了吗？ 放了，夫人
After our meeting, we're all going
to throw things at the prime minister.
在艾伯特礼堂的集会结束后，我们将去唐宁街……
把这些东西扔在首相的身上
你今天早上看上去非常好，乔治
How distinguished you look today.
What's all that fearful caterwauling?
厨房里那可怕的噪声是怎么回事？
It's cook singing.
那是厨师在唱歌 唱歌？她怎么了？
- What's wrong with her?
- She's happy as a cricket.
她快乐得像一只蟋蟀，老实讲……
Since you hired Mary Poppins,
从你雇用玛丽?泼平斯那天起，这屋子里似乎发生了……
the most extraordinary thing
has come over the household.
不同寻常的变化 有这回事？
- Ellen hasn't broken a dish all morning.
- That is extraordinary.
就拿艾伦来说吧，她今早没有打碎一只盘子
真的？那太不同寻常了 还有……
She and cook fight
like cats and dogs, but today...
他和厨师总是像猫见了狗一样打个不停，但是今天
- I'll hold the door.
- Thanks ever so.
艾伦，亲爱的，我来给你开门吧 谢谢
Ellen, stop making that offensive noise.
艾伦，快停止你那恐怖的歌声吧！
And shut the window.
That bird's giving me a headache.
把窗户关上，那鸟叫得我头痛
Yes, sir.
是的，先生
Quiet!
You're giving the master a headache.
安静点，你们闹得主人头痛
I'm sorry you're unwell.
我很担心你今天早上感觉不好
Who said I'm unwell?
谁说我的感觉不好？我非常健康
I just don't understand why
everyone's so confoundedly cheerful.
我只是搞不懂为什么每个人都这么兴奋
Supercalifragilisticexpialidocious
超级霹雳快乐得不得了
How lovely. Thank you, my darling.
这花真可爱，谢谢，宝贝！
Supercalifragilisticexpialidocious
超级霹雳快乐得不得了
Stop, stop, stop!
停！停！停！ 早上好，父亲
- Good morning, Father.
- Morning.
Mary Poppins taught us...
早上好 玛丽?泼平斯教给我们最有趣的一个词
Supercalifragilisticexpialidocious
超级霹雳快乐得不得了
What are you talking about?
Supercali...
你们到底在说些什么？超级……
究竟是什么意思？
Whatever it is.
It's something to say when
you don't know what to say.
当你不知道该说什么的时候，你就可以这样说
Yes, well, I always know what to say.
但是我总是知道我该说些什么，走开，请你们快点离开这里
- Yes, hurry along, please.
- Yes, Father.
好的，父亲 超级霹雳快乐得不得了
Supercalifragilisticexpialidocious
Winifred, will you explain
this unseemly hullabaloo?
威妮弗蕾德，你能解释一下这不体面的喧闹究竟是为什么吗？
I don't think there's
anything to explain.
我没觉得有什么需要解释的
The children just came in
to make you feel better.
很明显你今天早晨有点不舒服
孩子们近来只是想让你感觉好一些
I should like to be quite clear.
我最后一次声明
I am not out of sorts.
I'm in a perfectly equable mood.
我并没有感到不舒服，我的状态很好
I do not require
being made to feel better!
我不需要别人的安慰
You're always saying you want
a cheerful and pleasant household.
但是你常说希望我们的家充满了欢乐和愉快
I should like to make a differentiation
between cheerful and...
威妮弗蕾德，在愉快和轻率不负责任之间……
我要做一点区分
Excuse me, dear.
打断一下，亲爱的，大家各就各位！
Posts, everyone, please!
I have no objection to cheerfulness.
我并不反对任何人的欢乐和愉快
I expect certain decorum.
但我坚持合乎传统的礼仪
I don't propose standing idly by
我要告诉你的是，我不会袖手旁观
and letting Poppins
undermine the discipline...
看着那个女人，玛丽?泼平斯摧毁这个家庭的规矩
There's something extremely odd
about this household
自从她来了以后
这房子里出了很多非常奇怪的事情
since that woman arrived,
and I've noticed it.
我想让你知道，我已经注意到了 是的，亲爱的
Yes, dear.
One thing more.
还有件事情 什么，亲爱的？
Yes, dear?
Have this piano repaired.
找个人把钢琴修理一下
I like to have it in tune.
当我坐在一件乐器前面的时候，我希望它别走调
But, George, you don't play.
可是，乔治，你平常不弹呀！
That is entirely beside the point!
夫人，这并不重要！
Now, let me see.
让我来看看，首先，我们得去找一位调音师
We must go to the piano tuners,
then to Mrs Cory's shop
for some gingerbread,
然后去考利夫人的……
商店，买些姜味面包 哈，姜味面包！
then to the fishmonger's
for dover sole and prawns.
然后还要到鱼贩那儿买一尾新鲜的鳎科鱼
以及一品脱对虾
Michael,
stop stravaging along behind.
呃，迈克尔，别在后头慢慢吞吞的
Ahoy, there!
哈嗨！
Ahoy!
- Good day to you.
- Good morning, Admiral.
很高兴见到你们 早上好，将军
What fine adventure
are we off upon today?
迈克尔，今天我们去哪儿探险？
Going to fight the Hottentots?
是去和霍屯督人战斗，还是去寻找宝藏？
Dig for buried treasure?
We're going to buy fish.
我们打算去买点鱼
Very good. Proceed at flank speed.
非常好！全速前进
Aye, aye, sir.
遵命，长官
Let's put our backs into it.
小伙子，让我们继续
More spit and polish.
That's what's wanted.
注意外表整洁，这是这儿的规矩
Andrew.
是安德鲁
Woof! Woof! Woof!
Slow down. I can't understand a word.
唔，不要太快，我一个字都没听清你说的
Woof! Woof! Woof!
Again?
又发作了？可怜的人！
The poor man.
Woof! Woof! Woof!
Woof! Ah-choo!
Bless you.
天主保佑你
Woof! Woof! Woof!
Why, yes, certainly.
I'll go straight-away.
当然，不能耽搁，我们立刻就去
- Thank you very much.
- Woof!
非常感谢你
- What did he say?
- "You're welcome."
他说了什么？ 他说，不客气
- And?
- He didn't say anything.
他还说了什么？ 我认为他什么都没有说
You know best.
你总是什么都知道
I thought we were buying fish.
我以为我们要去买点鱼 计划有些变动
There's been a change of plans.
Come along, please. Don't straggle.
跟上，别走丢了
Andrew, worrying won't help anyone.
安德鲁，担心起不了任何作用
You should go home and rest.
你为何不回家休息休息一会儿呢？
Woof!
哦，伯特，很高兴你也在这里 我已听说就立即赶过来了
- Bert, I'm glad you're here.
- I came right away.
How is he?
他怎么样了？
He's never been worse.
说实话，我从来没见他这么糟糕过
How about them?
It's contagious, you know.
他们怎么跟来了？你知道，这病有传染性
- We'll get spots?
- Unlikely.
我们会长水痘吗？ 绝对不会的
Ohh! Hoo hoo hoo!
Oh, Uncle Albert.
哦，艾伯特叔叔 天主保佑，保佑我的灵魂
Bless my soul.
It's Mary Poppins. I'm delight... Ha-ha!
是玛丽?泼平斯，我很高兴
I'm delighted to see you.
我很高兴见到你，玛丽 艾伯特叔叔，你发过誓的
Uncle Albert, you promised.
Ha-ha! I know.
我知道……
I tried, really, I did.
I... Ho ho!
我努力了，真的……
But I so enjoy laughing.
Ah ha ha!
但是我太喜欢笑了，你知道吗？
When I start, it's up with...
Ha ha ha!
我一旦笑起来，就无法控制
That's what happens.
就像现在这样
I love to laugh! Ah ho ho!
我喜欢笑！我的天！
Oh, my! I can't help it.
你看到了，我情不自禁
Ha ha ha!
I just like laughing.
我就是喜欢笑，没别的
Ha ha! Ha ha!
Don't you dare.
You'll only make him worse.
简，你敢！你会让他病情恶化的！
- It's quite serious.
- Keep a straight face.
情况确实挺严重的 是的，无论如何，你都必须保持严肃
Last time,
we took three days to get him down.
上次，我们花了三天时间才把他弄下来
I love to laugh
我爱欢笑
Hoo hoo hoo hoo!
Loud and long and clear
爽朗的清晰的长久的笑
Ha!
I love to laugh
我爱欢笑
Ha ha ha ha!
It's getting worse every year
一年比一年严重
Ha ha ha!
The more I laugh
我越是笑
Ho ho ho!
The more I fill with glee
就越是感到高兴
You're no help!
你在这里起不到任何帮助 越是高兴
The more the glee
Ha ha ha ha!
The more I'm a merrier me
我就越是一个愉快的人
Hoo hoo hoo!
It's embarrassing.
这很令人为难
The more I'm a merrier me
我就越是一个愉快的人
Ha ha ha ha ha ha!
Ha ha ha ha!
Some people
laugh through their noses
有些人从鼻子里笑出来
Sounding something like this
听上去就像这样
Mmm-hmm hmm hmm!
Dreadful.
真烦人！
Sss-sss-sss!
Some people laugh through their teeth
Goodness sakes
有些人从牙缝里笑出声来
Hissing and fizzing like snakes
嘶嘶嘶，就像一条蛇
Sss sss sss!
Not at all attractive.
依我看，一点意思都没有
Some laugh too fast
有些人笑得很快
Hee hee hee hee!
Some only blast
有些笑得很短暂
Ha!
Others they twitter like birds
其他人，就像鸟儿一样咯咯地笑
Hee hee hee hoo!
You're as bad as he is.
你知道么，你和他一样严重
Then there's that kind
what can't make up their mind
有一种人从不掩饰他们的情绪
Hmm hmm hmm, ha ha ha!
Hee hee hee, ho ho ho!
Hee ha ho huh?
When things strike me as funny
I can't hide it inside
当有趣的事情向我袭来
我无法将它隐藏
And squeak, hee,
as the squeakelers do
不得不哈哈大笑
Ha ha ha!
I've got to let go
只要一开始笑，就得开怀大笑
With a ho ho ho ho
Ha ha ha ha!
And a ho ho ho, hoo!
然后
哈哈大笑
How nice!
太好了！
I was hoping you'd turn up.
我一直期待你也来
We always have a jolly time.
我们在一起过得很愉快
We love to laugh
我们爱笑
Ha ha ha ha!
Loud and long and clear
爽朗的清晰的长久的笑
Hoo hoo hoo!
We love to laugh
我们爱笑
Ha ha ha ha!
So everybody can hear
这样每个人都能听到
Ha ha ha!
The more you laugh
你越是笑
Don't you start. Come back here.
哎哟，你们两个别笑，回来
We fin with glee
你越是充满快乐
Hee hee hee!
And the more the glee
你越是快乐
Ha ha ha ha!
The more we're a merrier we
我们就越是愉快的人
Welcome, children. Welcome.
Make yourselves comfortable.
欢迎你们，小朋友，请随意
Pull up a chair.
没错，把椅子拉上来
是的，拉上来……
I say, you're a sight.
我不得不说你们是在出洋相
Speaking of sight,
it reminds me of me brother.
说到出洋相，我倒是想起我的哥哥
He works in a watch factory.
他在钟表厂有一份轻松的工作
What's he do?
在钟表厂？他做什么？
He stands about all day
and makes faces.
他一整天闲着做鬼脸（作钟表面）
Makes faces in a watch factory!
他在一家钟表厂做鬼脸……
You made that up.
你编的吧？
That's good.
太好了
Such behaviour.
瞧瞧你们的样子
It's disgraceful
or my name isn't Mary Poppins.
这是我见过的最不光彩的一幕，我情愿我不再叫玛丽?泼平斯
I know a man
with a wooden leg named Smith.
说到名字，我知道一个有一只木头假腿的人，名字叫史密斯 （也可理解为：我知道有个人，他有一只叫做史密斯的木头假腿）
What's the name of his other leg?
那他的另一条腿叫什么？
Wasn't that funny?
What's the name of...
很有意思吧？那他的另一条腿叫什……
Children, it's tea time.
I won't have schedule interruptions.
孩子们，下午茶时间到了
我可不愿意我的日程被打乱
Please stay.
哦，请留步，看，我已经为你们准备了上好的茶
Look, I have tea ready for you.
And it's getting cold.
这茶已经凉了
I had hoped that maybe you would...
我本以为你会……
Splendid! Thank you very much.
好极了！非常感谢！
Mind the bread and butter.
请把脚收回去。啊，当心面包和黄油
Now watch, children.
I knew she'd do it... A proper tea.
我知道她会这样做的。 这也是合乎传统的茶。
I suppose you'll want me to pour.
我猜，你想要我做的下一件事情就是为你倒茶
If I must, I must.
好吧，如果有必要，我一定去做
But stop behaving
like laughing hyenas.
如果你们不要像一群笑个不停的猎狗
- Two lumps, Uncle Albert?
- Yes, please.
两块糖吗？艾伯特叔叔？ 是的，谢谢
- Bert?
- None for me.
伯特，你呢？ 噢，不，不，不要糖
I'm glad you came.
It wouldn't be fun otherwise.
我很高兴你上来。如果你不来的话，就不好玩了
Pour some milk
for Michael and yourself.
给你自己还有迈克尔加点牛奶
- Nice weather we're having.
- Yes.
你不觉得今年的这个时候天气非常的好吗？
哦，是的。呃，谈到天气……
The other day when it was cold,
a friend bought long underwear.
有一天，天很冷
我的一个朋友想去买件长一点的内衣
The shopkeeper said,
"How long do you want it?"
售货员问，你打算要多长的（也可理解为：你打算要穿多久的）
My friend said,
"From September to March."
我的朋友回答说，大概从9月到3月
Jane! Control yourself!
简！别太放肆了！
Children, please sit up properly.
孩子们，麻烦你们坐到桌子旁边来
- Your tea, Uncle Albert.
- Thank you, dear.
你的茶，艾伯特叔叔 噢，谢谢，亲爱的
I'm having fun.
我很开心，多么希望你们能一直留在这里啊
I wish you could always stay here.
We'll have to. There's no way down.
我们很高兴不得不留下，因为没有路下去
Oh, there is a way.
哦不，路是有的
I hate mentioning it because
you must think of something sad.
坦诚地讲，我不愿提起它……
因为你得不得不想一些悲伤的事情
Do it, please.
那么请开始吧
Let me see.
让我想想看
I've got the very thing.
我知道一件非常合适的事情
Yesterday, when my neighbour
answered the bell, a man was there.
昨天隔壁的女士应声去开门，一个人站在门外
The man said, "I'm terribly sorry.
I just ran over your cat."
他对女士说，我非常抱歉，我刚刚轧了你的猫
哦，真悲惨 可怜的猫咪
- Oh, that's sad.
- The poor cat.
Then he said, "I'll replace your cat."
接着，那个人说，我很愿意替代那只猫
She said,
"Okay, but can you catch mice?"
女士说，可以，但有一点，你捉老鼠的技术好不好？
I started out saying...
我真的很努力让自己伤心点，但是……
I try.
Really, I do.
一切都那么好笑，我不能……
But everything ends up so hilarious.
I can't...
I can't help...
我禁不住……
That will be enough of that.
这已经够了
It's time to go home.
我们该回家了
Oh, that is sad. Oh, no.
唉，那太让人难过了 哦，不！
That's the saddest thing I ever heard.
那是我听过的最难过的事情了
Come along, children.
来吧，孩子们
Must you really go?
你们必须得走吗？
People come to see me all the time,
and we have such a lovely time.
你知道，大家来看望我
我们一起过得很愉快，然而他们不得不回家
Then they go home,
and I'm very, very sad about it.
对此我会感到非常非常的伤心
Don't worry.
We'll return soon.
别难过，我们会很快再来的
It was lovely.
我们过得非常开心
- Keep an eye on him, Bert.
- I'll stay a while.
伯特，照顾好艾伯特叔叔，好吗？
我会再陪他呆一会儿的 谢谢，来吧
Thank you.
Uncle Albert,
艾伯特叔叔，我有一个笑话专门留给这样的场合的
I got a jolly joke I saved for
just such an occasion.
- Want to hear it?
- I'd be so grateful.
你想听听看吗？ 好啊，我非常感激
Righto. It's about me granddad.
不必客气，这是关于我爷爷的
One night, he had a nightmare.
有一天晚上，我爷爷做了一个恶梦
So scared he chewed his pillow to bits.
他害怕极了，以至于把枕头咬成了碎片
成了碎片……第二天早晨，我说……
Next morning, I says,
"How do you feel?"
你感觉还好吗？爷爷？
He says, "A little down in the mouth."
他回答，呃，不坏，只是有点口干
There's nothing like a good joke.
我常说，没有什么东西比得上一个好笑话
No, and that's nothing like a good joke.
确实是，啥也比不上好笑话
Bit late tonight, aren't you?
班克斯，你今晚晚了些，是吗？
I say, Banks!
我说，班克斯！出了什么问题了，班克斯？
Is anything the matter, Banks?
Banks!
班克斯！
We're so glad you're home!
噢，父亲，真高兴你回来了 想听个笑话吗？
We had the most wonderful afternoon.
我们今天下午和玛丽?泼平斯在一起过得非常愉快
I know a man
with a wooden leg named Smith.
说到下午的事情，那个笑话是这样的
我知道有个人名字叫史密斯，他有条假腿
We don't know anyone
called Smith.
史密斯？我们不认识叫史密斯的人
The second chap says,
"What's his other leg's name?"
笑话还没有讲完，另一个家伙问，他的另一条腿叫什么名字
And a party on the ceiling.
我们还在天花板上开了一个非常棒的茶会
Children, be quiet.
哦，孩子们，请安静
Mary Poppins says we'll go again.
玛丽?泼平斯说，如果我们乖，她还会带我们去那儿的
Oh?
哦，玛丽?泼平斯这样说的吗？
Oh, Mary Poppins said that?
Please return to your room.
请回到你们自己的房间去，好吗？
Mary Poppins, will you come with me?
玛丽?泼平斯，请随我来好吗？
As you wish.
好的
Mary Poppins, I regret what I must say.
玛丽?泼平斯，我很遗憾，有些话我不得不说
Good evening, George.
ls anything the matter?
晚上好，乔治，有什么问题吗？ 我恐怕是的
I'm afraid so.
我很想留下来，但是我不得不换衣服了，因为今晚还有个集会
I have to dress for my rally.
- I'd rather you be present.
- Of course, George.
威妮弗蕾德，我希望你能留下来
好的，乔治，当然
Mary Poppins,
I confess I'm disappointed in you.
玛丽?泼平斯，我不得不说，我对你感到非常失望
She's for it. I've heard this before.
终于轮到她了，我以前就听过主人这样讲话
I don't deny I'm partially responsible
我不否认对于孩子们将全部的时间……
for allowing
the children's worthless frivolity.
都浪费在毫无意义的游戏上，我应该承担一定的责任
But they must learn
the seriousness of life.
但是，现在已经到了让他们认识到生活的严肃性的时候
But they're only children.
但是，乔治，他们还是孩子
In light of what's happened...
精确地讲，鉴于已经发生的……
George, are you certain?
乔治，你肯定你在说些什么吗？
我相信我知道，威妮弗蕾德
I believe I am.
A British bank is run with precision
一家英国银行运作于准确无误的基础之上
A British home requires nothing less
一个英国家庭也要运作与丝毫不差的基础上
Tradition, discipline, and rules
must be the tools
传统，纪律和规则是我们必须的工具
Without them
disorder, chaos, moral disintegration
没有了它们，混乱，无序……
道德崩溃
In short, you have a ghastly mess
总之，带来的是可怕的，混乱不堪的局面 我非常赞同
I quite agree.
The children must be
moulded, shaped and taught
孩子们必须被引导，塑造和教导
That life's a looming battle
to be faced and fought
生活是一场终究要面对和参与的战斗
I'm disturbed to hear my children
talking about popping into pictures,
总之，我很惊讶地听到我的孩子们讨论……
跑到马路上的粉笔画里……
consorting with racehorse persons,
fox hunting...
与驯马师联欢，猎狐
I don't mind that. It's tradition.
当然，这件事本身我并不反对
毕竟，它是传统的活动
But parties on the ceiling?
但是，在天花板上的茶会，请问是怎么回事？
Having tea parties on the ceiling?
在天花板上开茶会，以及其它各种令人疑惑的出游！
And other highly questionable outings...
If they must go on outings
如果他们必须出游的话，那么，出游应该有
These outings ought to be fraught
with purpose, yes, and practicality
明确的目标和……是的，实际意义
These silly words like
还有那些愚蠢的话
Superca...
比如超……超级……
Super...
Supercal...
超级霹…… 超级霹雳快乐得不得了
Supercalifragilisticexpialidocious.
Yes, well done.
是的，很好，就是你说的
And popping through pictures
have little use, fulfil no basic need
到画里面
毫无疑义，没有任何必要
They've got to learn the honest truth
Despite their youth
他们需要开始认识真正的现实
尽管年纪还小，他们必须学会……
They must learn
About the life you lead
向您那样的生活 正是如此
Exactly.
They must feel the thrill
of totting up a balanced book
他们需要体会统计分类帐差额簿的兴奋
A thousand ciphers neatly in a row
成千个数字整齐地排成一行 很对
Quite right.
When gazing at a graph
that shows the profits up
当瞥一眼显示利润上升的图标
Their little cup of joy should over?ow
兴奋就溢满他们那小小的心灵 的确如此
Precisely.
It's time they learnt
to walk in your footsteps
他们应该学着沿着你的脚印走路 是的
My footsteps.
满怀骄傲地沿着你的笔直且狭窄的道路前进 带着骄傲
To tread your straight
and narrow path with pride
With pride.
明天，正如你所建议的那样
Tomorrow, just as you suggest
Pressed and dressed
Jane and Michael will be at your side
简和迈克尔将会穿着整齐地和你一起
Splendid! You've hit the nail...
好极了，你说的准确无误……
At my side? Where are we going?
和我一起？去哪儿？
To the bank.
当然是去银行，完全按照您的建议
- The bank?
- Yes.
我的建议？ 当然
Tomorrow's an important day.
现在，如果你不介意，明天对于孩子们来讲是个重要的日子
I'll see they
have a proper night's sleep.
我要让他们睡个好觉，晚安
Did I say
I'd take the children to the bank?
威妮弗蕾德，我说过要带孩子们去银行吗？
It sounded that way.
听上去确实是的，亲爱的 哦
And why not?
为什么不呢？一个极好的主意！
Capital idea.
Just the medicine they need for all this
sugary female thinking they get here.
这正是对付眼下混乱局面的一剂良药
他们在这里接触的都是女人的不切实际的想法
Quite right. Good idea.
好主意，非常好
Quite right.
Mary Poppins, we won't let you go.
玛丽?泼平斯，我们不让你走
What do you mean?
走？你们到底在说什么？
Weren't you sacked?
你不是被解雇了吗？ 解雇？当然没有！我从来没有被解雇过！
Sacked? I am never sacked.
- Oh, Mary Poppins!
- Hooray!
哦，玛丽?泼平斯！ 好噢，好噢
Neither am I a maypole.
我也不是五朔节花柱，请别围着我转。
- But. ..
- Goats butt.
但 但什么但……
Birds fly.
Children going out with their father
get some sleep.
孩子们，你们必须早点睡觉，明天要跟你们的父亲一起出去
别这样，求求你 跟父亲出去？
An outing with Father?
是的 我不信
He's never taken us on an outing.
他以前从来没有带我们出去过 他从来没有带我们去任何地方
He's never taken us anywhere.
How did you manage it?
你怎么做到的？ 做到什么？
You gave him the idea.
你一定用了什么方式把这主意塞到他的脑瓜里了
How impertinent!
胡说！
Me giving ideas to people? Really.
我怎么可能把主意塞进人们的脑袋里？真是的！
- Where's he taking us?
- The bank.
他要带我们去哪里？ 去银行
Michael, the city!
Father can point out the sights.
哇~迈克尔，去城里！我们能看到好多风景，爸爸会指给我们看
Most things he can.
是的，多数风景他能发现
Sometimes people, through no fault
of their own, can't see past their nose.
但有时候，我们所爱的人却不能看到……
他眼皮底下的事情 眼皮底下的？
Past their nose?
Yes. Sometimes
a little thing is quite important.
是的，有时候一些小事情其实非常重要
Oh, look. The cathedral.
哦，看啊！这是主教座堂
Father passes that every day.
爸爸每天都从旁边经过，他常看到
Early each day
to the steps of St. Paul's
每天清晨，在圣保罗大教堂的台阶上
The little old bird woman comes
有一位孤独的老妇人
In her own special way
to the people she calls
用她自己独特的方式
向人们叫卖着
Come buy my bags full of crumbs
来买吧
鸟食
Come feed the little birds
喂喂这些小鸟
Show them you care
照顾它们
And you'll be glad if you do
你会感到快乐
Their young ones are hungry
它们的幼鸟非常饥饿
Their nests are so bare
它们的鸟巢非常简陋
All it takes is tuppence
只要花您两便士
From you
Feed the birds
来喂这些小鸟
Tuppence a bag
一袋两便士
Tuppence, tuppence
只要两便士
Tuppence a bag
两便士一袋
Feed the birds
来喂这些小鸟
That's what she cries
她正是这样叫卖
While overhead,
her birds fill the skies
在头顶上
鸟儿在空中盘旋
All around the cathedral
主教座堂顶上的所有圣人和使徒雕像
The saints and apostles
Look down as she sells her wares
都注视着她
Although you can't see it
虽然你看不见
You know they are smiling
但每次有人显示出
Each time someone shows
他的爱心，购买鸟食的时候
That he cares
你知道雕像们正在微笑
Though her words are simple and few
虽然老妇人的叫卖声
微弱而简单
Listen, listen
听，你听
She's calling to you
她在向你呼唤
Feed the birds
喂喂这些小鸟
Tuppence a bag
一袋两便士
Tuppence, tuppence
只要两便士
Tuppence a bag
两便士一袋
Though her words are simple and few
虽然老妇人的叫卖声
微弱而简单
Listen, listen
听，你听
She's calling to you
她在向你呼唤
Feed the birds
喂喂这些小鸟
Tuppence a bag
一袋两便士
Tuppence
只要两便士
Tuppence a bag
两便士
一袋
Now, remember.
Be on your best behaviour.
现在给我记住，银行是一个安静且庄重的地方。所以要表现出我们最好的举止
Isn't it your bank?
我还以为那是你的银行 好吧，我是银行里面一个年轻的职员……
As a younger officer, it is,
sort of.
所以在某种程度上是，有那么几分
Michael, look.
迈克尔，看！
It's her!
是她 谁？
- Who? It's who?
- The bird woman.
她是谁？ 卖鸟食的老妇人，就像玛丽?泼平斯所描述的
Just like Mary Poppins said.
You see her?
你确实看到她了，对吧，父亲？ 当然我能看到她
Of course I can. Do you think
I can't see past the end of my nose?
离我眼皮子这么近的我能看不到？
Listen, she's saying it.
听，父亲，她在叫卖
Feed the birds.
喂喂小鸟，一袋两便士
Tuppence a bag.
Of course she's saying it.
当然她在叫卖，她还能说别的什么吗？
- May we feed the birds?
- Whatever for?
我们能喂喂这些小鸟吗？ 为什么？
- I have tuppence.
- Just this once.
我从我的储蓄罐里面拿了两便士 就这一次，求求你了
Waste your money on birds?
Certainly not.
把你的钱浪费在一群肮脏的鸟身上？当然不行
But Mary Poppins...
但是玛丽?泼平斯说…… 我对玛丽?泼平斯说得话不感兴趣
I'm not interested in Mary Poppins
nor in hearing her name.
今天也不想再听到她的名字。现在快跟上来！
But it's my tuppence.
但这是我的两便士！
Michael, don't throw your money away!
迈克尔，我决不允许你把钱这样扔掉！
At the bank, I'll show you what to do.
等我们到了银行，我会教你该怎么处置你的两便士
It's extremely interesting.
我想你也会发现这会非常有意思
Hello, Banks. What's all this about?
你好，班克斯。这些都是谁？
My children.
道斯先生，它们都是我的孩子 我想也是
Why are they here?
但他们在这里干什么？ 他们想开一个户头
They're opening an account, sir.
真的？ 是的
How much money do you have?
那么年轻人，你有多少钱呢？
Tuppence. I want it to feed the birds.
两便士。但是我想用来买鸟食 嘘！
tuppence!
两便士
Tuppence...
两便士？恰好就是我起家的资金
Precisely how I started.
That's the elder Mr Dawes,
a giant in the finance world.
那是银行的主席，老道斯先生
金融界的一位伟人（也可翻译为巨人，大力士）
A giant?
一个大力士？ 嘘！
Father, these are Banks' children!
唔，父亲，这些是班克斯的孩子
They want to open an account!
他们想来开个户头 噢，是么，孩子？
Do they, boy? Excellent. Excellent.
好极了，好极了
我们总，总能让……
We can use more money
to put to work for the bank.
让钱发挥更大的作用，对吧？孩子
You have tuppence?
这么说，你有两便士？
May I be permitted to see it?
我能看看吗？
It's for feeding the birds.
不，我想用它来买鸟食，喂鸟
Feed the birds and what have you got?
胡说！喂鸟，你能得到什么？更胖的鸟？
Fat birds!
But...
但是，如果你把你的两便士
If you invest your tuppence
wisely in the bank
明智地存入银行
Safe and sound
两便士将完好无损
Soon that tuppence
很快，那安全地投资在银行里的两便士
Safely invested in the bank
Will compound
会滋生利息
And you'll achieve
that sense of conquest
当财富不断地膨胀
As your af?uence expands
你将获得成就感
In the hands of the directors
（你的钱）在一群
懂得
Who in vest
恰当投资的
As propriety demands
银行经理手中
- May I, sir?
- Carry on, Banks.
我来解释吧，先生？ 来吧，班克斯
You see, Michael, you'll be part of
railways through Africa!
你瞧，迈克尔，你将会成为如下项目的投资人……
穿越非洲大陆的铁路 完全正确
Exactly.
Dams across the Nile.
尼罗河大坝 还有那船，告诉他们船的投资
- Talk about the ships.
- Fleets of ocean greyhounds.
远洋快轮 还有，都告诉他们
Tell them more.
Majestic self-amortizing canals.
伟大的自我分期还贷的运河
It fires the imagination!
哦，想象力真丰富！
Plantations of ripening tea
成熟的大庄园
茶叶
All from
所有的这一切都来自于
Tuppence
将两便士明智地，成功地，节俭地
Prudently, thriftily, frugally
invested in the...
投资在 这很明确
To be specific
In the Dawes, Tomes,
Mousley, Grubbs
道斯 托姆斯 莫斯利 格鲁布斯
Fidelity Fiduciary bank
信托投资银行
Give me the money, boy.
很好，孩子，把钱给我 不，我不要，我要拿去买鸟食喂鸟
I want to feed the birds.
Banks!
班克斯！ 是的，先生，马上给他，迈克尔
Yes, sir. Now, Michael...
When you deposit
tuppence in a bank account
当你在银行的户头上存入两便士
Go on!
继续 很快你将看见
Soon you'll see
Tell him more!
都告诉他！ 半年后，它将
That it blooms
into credit of a generous amount
Semi-annually
发展成为一笔巨大的财富
And you'll achieve that sense of stature
当财富不断地膨胀
As your influence expands
你将获得成就感
To the high financial strata
建立信贷机构的
That established credit now commands
金融界最高层人士现在宣布
You can purchase
first and second trust deeds.
你可以购买第一和第二类信托契约
Imagine the foreclosures,
想象一下回赎抵押品权利的取消所发生的事情吧！
bonds, chattels, dividends, shares.
债券，个人资产，股息，股票
Bankruptcies.
破产 债权转让
Debtor sales.
机遇 各种形形色色的私人企业
Opportunities.
Private enterprise.
Shipyards.
船坞 商船
- The mercantile.
- Collieries.
煤矿 皮革厂
Tanneries.
Corporations, amalgamations.
公司 合并 银行
Banks!
While stand the Banks of England,
当英格兰的银行兴旺时……
England stands.
英格兰屹立不倒
When fall the Banks of England,
但英格兰的银行倒闭时……
England falls!
英格兰没落
You see, Michael?
你看到么吗，迈克尔？所有这一切都因
All for the lack of...
Tuppence
缺乏对两便士进行耐心地，谨慎地
Patiently
Cautiously
Trustingly invested in the...
信赖地投资在
To be specific
这很明确
In the Dawes, Tomes,
Mousley, Grubbs
道斯 托姆斯 莫斯利 格鲁布斯
Fidelity Fiduciary Bank
信托投资银行
Welcome to our joyful
family of investors.
欢迎来到我们这个快乐的投资者大家庭
Give it back!
还给我！把钱还给我！
Michael, behave...
迈克尔，注意你的举止 班克斯！ 把钱还给我！
Give it to him.
迈克尔，听话！简！简！ 把钱还给我！
Give me back my money!
简！迈克尔！迈克尔！迈克尔！
把钱还给我！ 迈克尔！
The bank won't
give someone their money.
出了什么问题。银行拒绝兑现了
I'm getting mine.
天，我要拿回我的钱！你，年轻人，我要取回每一分钱！
Come along, every penny!
And give me mine, too.
我也要！ 还有我的！
Stop all payments.
停止兑付！
迈克尔！简！ 把钱还给我！
Give me my money!
Children, come back!
孩子们，回来，拦住那些孩子，简！迈克尔！
- Stop those children!
- Jane! Michael!
还给我钱！还我钱！
Come on!
来吧
拦住那些孩子！
Stop those children!
拦住孩子！
Aah!
Come with me.
跟我来，亲爱的。我帮你藏起来
Granny will hide you!
Aah!
Here, half a mo.
这儿，这儿，等一下 放开她，把我的姐姐放开！
Leave my sister alone.
Your friend won't hurt you.
嘿，没事的，你们的老朋友不会伤害你的
Bert, it's you.
伯特，是你啊！
In the flesh and at your service.
正是在下，听从你的吩咐
You're filthy.
你可真脏！ 哦，也许是有一两处污渍
Perhaps a smudge.
It so happens
today I'm a chimney sweep.
碰巧今天我是个扫烟囱的人
Oh, Bert, we're so frightened.
哦，伯特，我们吓得要命
好了，好了，现在不用害怕
Don't take on so.
Bert will take care of you.
Like I was your own father.
伯特会向你们的父亲那样照顾好你们的
Who's after you?
谁在追你们？ 我们的父亲……
Father.
What?
什么？ 他带我们去他的银行参观
We went to his bank.
We must have done
something dreadful.
我不知道我们做了什么，但一定是非常糟糕的事情
The police and army were after us.
他让警察追我们，还有军队，所有人都在追我们
Michael, don't exaggerate.
迈克尔，别这么夸张
There must be some mistake.
好吧，一定有什么误会
Your dad loves you.
你们的爸爸是个好人，他爱你们
No, not with the look he had on his face.
不可不这样认为。你最好能看见他当时的那张脸
He doesn't like us.
他压根就不喜欢我们
好了，别好像好像的，好吗？
That don't seem likely, does it?
It's true.
这是事实
Let's sit down.
让我们坐一坐
Begging your pardon,
你知道，……
but my heart goes out to your father.
我很同情你们的父亲
There he is in that cold,
heartless bank,
他在那个冷酷的，无情的银行中日复一日地……
hemmed in by mounds
of cold, heartless money.
被一大堆冰冷的，无感情的金钱所包围
I don't like seeing
living things caged up.
我不喜欢看到任何生命被关在笼中
父亲被关在笼子里了？
Father in a cage?
Cages come in all sizes and shapes,
笼子的尺寸和形状不同而已，你知道
even bank-shaped.
一些是银行形状的，用地毯什么的来制作
父亲没有麻烦，我们有！
Father's not in trouble, we are.
Sure about that, are you?
哦，你们确信？
You've got your mother
to look after you,
换个角度想想，你们有你们的母亲照顾你们
and Mary Poppins
and Constable Jones and me.
还有玛丽?泼平斯，琼斯警察，还有我
Who looks after your father?
谁来照顾你们的父亲呢？你们说说看
When something happens,
what does he do?
当一些可怕的事情发生时，他该怎么办？
Fends for himself, he does.
他只能自己照顾自己
Who does he tell?
他向谁倾诉？没人！
No one.
Don't blab his troubles.
不能在家里倾诉他的烦心事
He pushes on at his job,
他只是毫无怨言，独自一人，安静地努力承受着
uncomplaining, alone, and silent.
He's not very silent.
他并不是很安静！ 迈克尔，安静点
Michael, be quiet.
Bert, does Father really need our help?
伯特，你确定父亲真的需要我们的帮助吗？
It's not my place to say.
呃，这个我不该说的
But fathers can always do
with a bit of help.
我只注意到，一个父亲常常需要那么一点帮助
I'll take you home.
来吧，我带你们回家
Chim chiminy chim chiminy
Chim chim cheree
黑烟囱……冒黑烟……
A sweep is as lucky as lucky can be
一个扫烟囱人就是幸运星
Chim chiminy chim chiminy
Chim chim cheroo
黑烟囱……冒黑烟……
Good luck will rub off
when I shakes hands with you
当我和你握手，好运就会传染给你
Or blow me a kiss
或者和我接吻
And that's lucky, too
好运也会传染给你
Now as the ladder of life
has been strung
当生活就想一串梯子
You might think a sweep's
on the bottommost rung
你可以想想在梯子最底端的扫烟囱人
Though I spends me time
in the ashes and smoke
虽然我成天跟炉灰打交道
In this whole wide world
there's no happier bloke
但在这整个广袤的世界里，没有其它家伙能比我更快乐
Chim chiminy chim chiminy
Chim chim cheree
黑烟囱……冒黑烟……
A sweep is as lucky as lucky can be
一个扫烟囱人就是幸运星
Chim chiminy chim chiminy
Chim chim cheroo
黑烟囱……冒黑烟……
Good luck will rub off
when I shakes hands with you
当我和你握手，好运就会传染给你
Chim chiminy chim chiminy
Chim chim cheree
黑烟囱……冒黑烟……
A sweep is as lucky as lucky can be
一个扫烟囱人就是幸运星
Chim chiminy chim chiminy
Chim chim cheroo
黑烟囱……冒黑烟……
Good luck will rub off
when I shakes hands with you
当我和你握手，好运就会传染给你
噢，艾伦，去看看是谁，把他们打发走
Ellen, whoever that is, send them away.
I'm dreadfully late.
我已经迟到了！ 是的，夫人
Yes, mum.
I'll be leaving.
好了，我现在可以离开了。 哦别，请陪我们到父亲回家来为止吧。
Please stay till Father comes home!
Father will feel better
如果你跟他握手，他会感觉好多的。
if you shake hands with him.
It's the children, mum.
是孩子们 我想他们应该跟他们的父亲在一起
I thought they were with their father.
You haven't been running off,
have you?
你们不是又逃跑了吧？你们知道这会让我多痛苦吗？
They haven't exactly been
running away, mum.
哦夫人，准确地讲他们并不是逃跑
然而，他们受了点惊吓，需要有人照顾
They've been frightened
and should be looked after.
哦，当然！玛丽?泼平斯会照顾他们的
Oh, of course, Mary Poppins will...
Oh, no, it's her day off.
噢，不，今天她休假
Ellen, would you...
艾伦，我想请你…… 不行，夫人，我自己的活还没有干完呢
No, mum. I haven't done me brasses.
Ask Mrs Brill...
好吧，你能问一下布里夫人吗？ 就算给我一百英镑，我也不干，夫人
Not for 100 quid.
It's baking day,
and you know how cook is.
今天是烘焙日，你知道要煮多少东西么！
What about you, sir?
你怎么样，先生？
You've been so kind.
你刚才已经非常热心地照顾这些孩子了
Me, mum?
唔……我吗？夫人，我……我不得不离开
Lord mayor's got
a stopped-up chimney.
市长大人家的烟囱被堵住了
How clever of you to know.
烟囱，你可真聪明
我们客厅的烟囱糟糕透了。烟不断地往客厅冒
Our drawing room chimney
is in the most ghastly condition.
唔…… 非常谢谢！
Thank you so much.
Besides, it will amuse the children.
但，但是…… 还有，顺便带好孩子
The lord mayor's going
to be terrible put out.
市长大人家的马上就要剧烈地喷发了
Thank you so much.
哦，谢谢你，我会非常感激的
I do appreciate it.
I must hurry.
我必须得走了。我们勇敢的姐妹在监狱中正等着我领她们唱歌呢！
Our gallant ladies in prison
are waiting for me to lead them in song.
Good-bye, my darlings.
再见，亲爱的，一会儿见
I choose me bristles
with pride, yes, I do
我骄傲地挑选猪鬃工具，是的，我骄傲
A broom for the shaft
扫帚用来扫烟囱，用刷子来通烟道
And a brush for the ?ue
It's awfully dark and gloomy up there.
这里很黑很暗
You see how wrong people can be?
现在，你将知道你的看法是错误的
That's a doorway
to a place of enchantment.
这儿是通向你所谓魔法世界的一条通道
Up where the smoke
is all billowed and curled
在上面烟雾如巨浪般翻滚，卷曲
'Tween pavement and stars
在星星和地面之间
ls the chimney sweep world
是扫烟囱人的世界
When there's hardly no day
这里几乎没有白天
Nor hardly no night
也几乎没有黑夜
There's things half in shadow
所有的事物一半在阴影里
And halfway in light
一半在光线下
On the rooftops of London
站在伦敦的屋顶
Coo, what a sight
视野真开阔
我真希望我们能到上面去
I wish we could go up there.
我也是！我喜欢烟囱
I like chimneys.
非常正确！烟囱是一件完美的东西
Rightly so.
A chimney is a wondrous thing.
It's built tall up there on the roof.
她高高地建在屋顶上
The wind blows across her top
当风向正确的时候，风吹过她的顶端
and draws the smoke right up the flue.
驱动烟从烟道中穿过
Feel the pull on the end of that brush.
拿着，用刷子感受一下底部的吸力
It's like you've got a whale
at the end of the line, isn't it?
这就好像站在鲸鱼喷水口的底部
Michael, be careful.
迈克尔，小心，你永远不知道站在壁炉旁边会发生什么事情
Things happen around fireplaces.
Oh, bother.
天啦！
Michael!
迈克尔，迈克尔，下来！
Michael, come back down here!
Michael, Michael, where are you?
迈克尔，你在哪里？
That's a bit awkward.
好吧，我不得不说，这有点尴尬！
Stop putting ideas in their heads.
伯特，麻烦你不要出馊主意了！
There goes another one.
现在轮到下一个 我能跟在后面么？
Shall I go after them?
They can't
gallivant up there like kangaroos.
我们不能让他们像袋鼠一样在上面闲逛，对吧？
Michael, everything's going to be...
迈克尔，别害怕。事情正在……
Will you put your things on?
你能立刻把你的东西放下吗？
请快一点
Hurry up.
Spit spot.
Thought you'd left.
你在这儿！我以为你丢下我们了。 我们没有这个意思
We didn't mean to.
No harm done.
真好，一切平安无事。事实上……
Truth is, this is
a fortuitous circumstance.
这是你们所说的偶发事件
Look there.
看那儿
A trackless jungle
just waiting to be explored.
一个茂密的雨林正等着我们去探索
Why not, Mary Poppins?
为什么不行，玛丽?泼平斯？ 求求你了，玛丽?泼平斯
Oh, please, Mary Poppins.
Oh, well... if we must,
we must.
好吧，如果这是必要的
Fall in.
同意
精神点，精神点。跟上！跟上！
Look lively.
Jump to it.
Get in line.
排成一列，立正！
Attention!
Slope arms!
扛枪！
Right turn!
向右转！
Quick march!
齐步走！
Hello there!
喂，那儿！
It's just good clean soot,
Michael.
很好，擦干净，迈克尔
Far as we go, right?
我们只能走到这里了，是吗？ 当然不
Not at all.
What did I tell you?
我说什么来着？整个世界都在你脚下
The world's at your feet,
and who sees it but the birds,
只有鸟儿、星星和扫烟囱人见过
the stars, and the chimney sweeps?
Quite nice.
真棒，但我们必须走出这片夜色
But we've had enough night air.
Follow me, please.
请跟我来
黑烟囱……冒黑烟……
Chim chiminy chim chiminy
Chim chim cheree
When you're with a sweep
当你和一个扫烟囱人在一起，就如同与欢乐在一起
You're in glad company
Nowhere is there a more happier crew
哪儿都不如一群快乐的人群
Than them what sings
Chim chim cheree, chim cheroo
他们都这样唱着
Chim chiminy chim chim
Cheree chim cheroo
黑烟囱……冒黑烟……
冒黑烟……
Cheroo!
Cheroo! Cheroo!
It's all me pals!
这些都是我的哥们！
Step in time!
来跳舞！
Step in time! Step in time!
Step in time!
来跳舞！
Come on, mateys, step in time!
来吧，朋友，来跳舞
Step in time!
来跳舞
Step in time, step in time
Never need a reason
Never need a rhyme
从不需要原因，从不需要理由，我们来跳舞，来跳舞
Step in time, we step in time
Kick your knees up!
提起你的膝盖！
Kick your knees up, step in time
从不需要原因，从不需要理由
Never need a reason
Never need a rhyme
Kick your knees up, step in time
提起你的膝盖
Round the chimney!
围着烟囱！
Round the chimney, step in time
从不需要原因，从不需要理由
Never need a reason
Never need a rhyme
Round the chimney, step in time
围着烟囱！我们跳舞
Flap like a birdie!
像鸟儿一样拍打
Flap like a birdie, step in time
从不需要原因，从不需要理由
Never need a reason
Never need a rhyme
Flap like a birdie, in time
像鸟儿一样拍打
Up on the railing!
爬上栏杆
Up on the railing, step in time
从不需要原因，从不需要理由
Never need a reason
Never need a rhyme
Up on the railing, step in time
爬上栏杆
Over the rooftops!
跨过屋顶
Over the rooftops, step in time
从不需要原因，从不需要理由
Never need a reason
Never need a rhyme
Step in time
跨过屋顶
Over the rooftops, over the rooftops
Link your elbows!
站成一排踢腿！
Link your elbows, step in time
站成一排踢腿
Link your elbows, link your elbows
Link your elbows
Step in time, step in time
来跳舞
Never need a reason
Never need a rhyme
从不需要原因，从不需要理由
When you step in time
You step in time
Mary Poppins, step in time!
玛丽?泼平斯，来跳舞！
There you go, Mary Poppins!
来吧，玛丽?泼平斯！
Lucky old Bert!
哦，伯特！
Come on, Mary Poppins!
来吧
来，伙计！
Here we go!
来
给她让点地方！
Ain't she marvellous?
她真不可思议！她真漂亮！
Ain't she beautiful?
Lovely. Tell your mum.
真可爱
Hello, hello, hello!
好啊
- More! More!
- Mary, do it again!
再来！玛丽?泼平斯，再来一遍！
Here we go.
我们来
We're being attacked by Hottentots!
我们正被霍屯督人攻击！ 是的，将军。
Aye, aye, sir.
Cheeky devils! Give them what for!
这帮魔鬼！ 给他们点教训！
Empty the shot lockers!
清空炮膛 遵命，将军！
Ave, aye, sir!
Move along, Mr Binnacle.
动起来，班纳克先生。慢一点，给这些乞丐一点教训。
Teach the beggars a lesson!
Gun ready, sir.
大炮准备好了，将军。 预备
Stand by.
Fire!
开火！
Well hit, sir!
正中目标！ 很好！
Very well hit!
Aah! They're at it again!
嘿！他们又来了！
They're at it again, step in time
他们又来了！
At it again, step in time
They're at it again, step in time
他们又来了
Ow!
Ow! Step in time
从不需要原因，从不需要理由
Never need a reason
Never need a rhyme
Whoa!
Step in time
Oh, Ellen, when you're free...
哦，艾伦，你什么时候有空。
Votes for women, step in time
争取妇女的投票权！
Not at the moment.
不，真的，这时候不行。
Votes for women
争取妇女投票权！
Votes for women!
It's the master!
主人回来了！
It's the master, step in time
It's the master
What's all this?
这都是些什么？
What's all this, what's all this
这都是些什么
What's all this
排成一列踢腿。来跳舞
Link your elbows, step in time
What's all this? What's all this?
提起你的膝盖
Kick your knees up
Kick your knees up...
伯特。
Bert.
提起你的膝盖
Good luck, guv'nor.
祝好运，老爸，多美好的时光
Lovely time.
Had an elegant time,
guv'nor.
祝你有个文雅的时光，老爸
Good luck, guv'nor.
祝好运，老爸
Father,
every sweep shook your hand.
哦，父亲，这些扫烟囱人都握过你的手
You'll be so lucky!
你将会变成世界上最幸运的人！
Come along, children.
Spit spot.
来吧，孩子们，快点 等一等，玛丽?泼平斯
One moment, Mary Poppins.
这简直是件骇人听闻的事件
What's the meaning of this?
I beg your pardon?
你再说一遍？ 你最好给我一个合理的解释
Will you explain all this?
I'd like to make one thing clear.
首先，我愿明确地解释一件事情
Yes.
什么？
I never explain anything.
我从不解释任何事
Yes? Banks here.
是，我是班克斯
Mr Dawes...
道斯先生！我非常非常的抱歉。关于今天在银行发生的事情
I'm dreadfully sorry
about what happened today.
I can assure you that...
我可以保证…… 今晚，先生？
Tonight, sir?
是的，班克斯。我们希望你9点准时到达
Yes. We'll expect you
at 9:00 precisely.
Without fail.
不能迟到
Why, yes, Banks.
为什么，班克斯。
It's extremely serious.
这是极其严重的事件
We regret this action.
我们对这一系列决定非常遗憾
我们非常遗憾
You've been with us many years...
毕竟，你和我们共事多年
毕竟，共事多年 在此之前是你的父亲
As was your father.
之前是你的父亲
Yes, Mr Dawes.
是的，道斯先生。我会9点到
I shall be there at 9:00.
A man has dreams
of walking with giants.
一个男人梦想着与巨人同行
在漫漫人生旅途中雕琢环境
To carve his niche in
the edifice of time.
在他的热情
Before the mortar of his zeal
Has a chance to congeal
凝固之前
The cup's dashed from his lips.
奖杯是奖励给冲过终点线的人！
The flame's snuffed aborning.
激情尚未迸发便被浇灭
He's brought to wrack
and ruin in his prime.
他在他全盛时期被毁灭
Life's a rum go,
guv'nor.
生活就像一杯朗姆酒，老爸。这是事实。
That's the truth.
I think it's Mary Poppins.
你知道我想什么吗？是那个女人——玛丽?泼平斯说的。
Since she's come,
从她踏进这所房子的那一刻开始，许多事情就发生了！
things have happened to me.
玛丽?泼平斯？ 是的，当然。
Mary Poppins?
Yes, of course!
My world was calm
我的世界曾经平静
Well ordered...
井然有序，值得效仿
Exemplary.
Then came this person
自打这个人带着被她唤醒的
With chaos in her wake
混乱，来了以后
And now my life's ambitions go
现在我生活的抱负一下子
With one fell blow
被打倒了
It's quite a bitter pill
这是相当难以
To take
表述的
That Poppins woman did it!
这就那个姓泼平斯的女人！就是她造成的！
我知道你说的这个女人
I know the person... Mary Poppins.
She's the one what sings...
玛丽?泼平斯，她就是那个唱着……
A spoonful of sugar
一汤匙糖
That is all it takes
那就是全部
It changes bread and water into
它把面包和水
变成了茶和蛋糕
Tea and cakes
That's it exactly!
你明白了吗？那正是我的意思！
Changing bread into cakes, indeed.
把面包和水变成茶和蛋糕！确实是！
No wonder
everything's higgledy-piggledy.
难怪这里每件事情都杂乱无章
A spoonful of sugar
一汤匙糖
Goes a long, long way
每天走很长很长的路
Have yourself a healthy helpin'
有助于你的
Every day
健康
A healthy helpin' of trouble.
如果你问我，一个有益健康的问题
You know what she did? I realise it now.
She tricked me
你知道她怎么做的吗？我现在意识到了
她怂恿我带简和迈克尔来银行
into taking
Jane and Michael to the bank.
That's how the trouble started.
这正是所有麻烦的开始
Tricked you into that?
怂恿你带孩子们出门远足？ 是的
Outrageous!
真无耻！
A man as important as you?
一个男人有许多重要的事情要去做。真可耻！
Shameful!
You're a man of high position,
你是一个有身份的男人
esteemed by your peers.
受同龄人的尊敬
当你的孩子们哭泣的时候
And when your little tykes are cryin'
You haven't time to dry their tears
你没有时间去擦干他们的眼泪
And see them grateful little faces
瞧瞧他们感激地小脸蛋
Smilin' up at you
冲着你微笑
Because their dad
因为他们的爸爸
He always knows just what to do
总是知道什么是应该做的
I mean, look...
呃，我的意思是，瞧，我不认为我…… 就像你说的，老爸
Like you say,
guv'nor...
You've got to grind, grind, grind
你不得不在石磨上
At that grindstone
不停地磨呀磨呀磨
Though childhood slips
虽然童年时光
Like sand
就像沙子穿过沙漏
Through a sieve
And all too soon
很快他们就长大
They've up and grown
And then they've flown
接着他们就离你而去
And it's too late for you to give
那时你再后悔
就太迟了
Just that spoonful of sugar
就好像一汤匙糖
To help the medicine
能够帮助把药服下
Go down
The medicine go down
甜药
Medicine go down
好入口
Well, goodbye, guv'nor.
好了，再见，老爸，很抱歉给你惹了这么多麻烦
Sorry to have troubled you.
父亲？
Father.
We're sorry about the tuppence.
我们对两便士的事情非常抱歉
We didn't know it would
cause you so much trouble.
我们不知道那会引起这么大的麻烦
Here, Father.
You can have the tuppence.
父亲，给你两便士
Will that make everything all right?
这样能平息所有的风波吗？
Thank you.
谢谢
Come in!
进来!
把帽子脱掉，班克斯
Take your hat off, Banks.
晚上好，先生们
Good evening, gentlemen.
很好，继续
Get on with it. Go on.
是，父亲
Yes, Father.
In 1773,
an official of this bank
在1773年，这家银行的一位职员……
unwisely loaned a large
sum of money
愚蠢地将一大笔钱借给
to finance a shipment of tea
往北美殖民地海运茶叶的贸易
to the American colonies.
Do you know what happened?
知道后来发生了什么事？ 是的，先生，我想我知道
I do.
As the ship lay in Boston Harbour,
当船停泊在波士顿港的时候
colonists dressed as Red Indians
一群殖民地居民打扮成印第安人
登上了船，举止非常粗鲁，还将所有的茶叶倾倒到海里
boarded, behaved rudely,
and threw the tea overboard.
导致茶叶味道变质
This made the tea
unsuitable for drinking,
even for Americans.
即使是美国人也不愿意喝
Precisely.
很对。这笔借款成了呆账
The loan was defaulted.
Panic ensued within these walls.
在这堵墙内的恐慌接踵而至
There was a run on the bank.
银行发生了挤兑事件！
From that time to this,
从那时起到现在，先生……
这家银行还没有发生过一起挤兑事件
there has not been a run on this bank.
Until today!
直到今天！
A run, sir, caused by
the disgraceful conduct
一场挤兑事件，先生，起因是你儿子的可耻的行为
of your son.
Do you deny it?
对此你否认吗？ 我不否认，先生
No, sir.
我只能情愿为我儿子的行为承担责任
I shall gladly assume
responsibility for my son.
你还在等什么？继续！ 是，是的，父亲
Why are you waiting?
Get on with it.
Yes, Father.
不，别这样！ 镇定！
No, not that!
Steady on.
好了，班克斯，你还有什么话要说的吗？
Do you have anything to say?
先生，他们说……
Sir, they do say
that when there's nothing to say,
当你无话可说的时候，你就可以说……
all you can say...
Confound it, Banks!
班克斯，请搞清楚！我问，你还有什么说的吗？
Do you have anything to say?
Just one word, sir.
只有一个词，先生 什么词？
Yes?
超级霹雳快乐得不得了
Supercalifragilisticexpialidocious.
What?
什么？
超级霹雳快乐得不得了
Supercalifragilisticexpialidocious.
Mary Poppins was right.
玛丽?泼平斯是对的。这个词很特别，确实能让你感觉好多了！
It does make you feel better.
There's no such word.
你在说什么？没有这个词
It is a perfectly good word.
不，有这个词。实际上，它是一个完美的词
Do you know
what there's no such thing as?
你知道有这样的事情吗？
With due respect,
there's no such thing as you!
当所有的事情都说过并做过后，发生……
像你这样的事情……
Impertinence, sir!
主题，先生！注意谈话的主题
Would you like to hear
a marvellous joke?
你想听一个绝妙的笑话吗？
A real snapper.
一个真正的笑话！ 笑话？真正的？
Joke? Snapper?
是的，有两个优秀的年轻人，简和迈克尔
Jane and Michael
meet one day on the street.
有一天他们在街上相遇，简跟迈克尔说
Jane says, "I know a man
with a wooden leg named Smith."
我知道一个有一只木头假腿的人，名字叫史密斯 （也可理解为：我知道有个人，他有一只叫做史密斯的木头假腿）
迈克尔问，真的？那他的另一只腿叫什么？
Michael says,
"What's the name of his other leg?"
The man's gone mad.
Call the guard!
这个人疯了，叫警卫
Supercalifragilisticexpialidocious.
超级霹雳快乐得不得了，我感觉好极了！
I'm feeling better!
班克斯，不准你打击我的父亲！
Don't strike my father!
There's the tuppence,
the wonderful, fateful,
这是那两便士 这是命中注定的，绝妙的
超级霹雳快乐得不得了 的两便士
supercalifragilisticexpialidocious
tuppence.
Guard it well. Good-bye!
好好保护它，再见！ 班克斯，你要去哪儿？
Where are you going?
我不知道 也许跳进马路上的粉笔画里
I might pop through
a chalk pavement picture
去乡下远足
or seize a horse off a merry-go-round
或者骑着一匹旋转木马，赢得赛马比赛
or fly a kite.
或者仅仅去放风筝！这只有泼平斯知道！
Only Poppins knows.
- Poppins?
- My nanny.
泼平斯？ 我的保姆。那首荒谬的歌就是她唱的。
She sings that ridiculous song.
A spoonful of sugar
一汤匙糖让苦药服下
Makes the medicine go down
The medicine go down
甜药好入口
甜药好入口……
The medicine...
Mad as a March hare.
像三月里的野兔般疯狂
A wooden leg named Smith.
一只叫史密斯的木假腿
史密斯有条木假腿
A wooden leg named Smith.
A wooden le...
木假腿……
Father.
父亲？父亲！
Father!
Father, come down!
父亲，下来！
Daddy!
爸爸，爸爸！回来！
Daddy, come back!
Wind's come around,
风向转变了，非常精确地从西边刮来！
blowing dead on from the west.
She doesn't care what happens to us.
她不关心我们身上发生的事情
她只答应呆到风向转变为止。是吧，玛丽?泼平斯？
She only promised to stay
till the wind changed, right?
Bring my hat stand, please.
请把衣帽架递过来好吗？
Mary Poppins, don't you love us?
玛丽?泼平斯，你不爱我们了吗？
What would happen to me
不关心我们的遭遇了吗？
if I loved all the children
I said goodbye to?
请问如果我爱所有的小孩，我该给谁告别呢？
That's right. George W. Banks,
是的，先生，没错。乔治 W 班克斯
樱桃树大街17号
17 Cherry Tree Lane.
About 6'1", I'd say.
大约6英尺高，是的。
Yes, we rang up his bank first thing.
是的，今天早上第一件事情就是给他工作的银行打了电话
目前我们所知道的唯一事情就是，他昨晚就已经离开了
We discovered he'd
been discharged last night.
No telling what he'll do
in a fit of despondency.
他很沮丧，没说要干什么
不会去投河吧？
Wouldn't hurt to drag the river.
There's a spot popular with jumpers.
在萨克福桥附近有一个非常合适的地点，因投河自尽而闻名
Really, Ellen!
真的，艾伦！
他看上去还不错，很镇定，先生
He seemed to have been
a fine, stable gentleman.
没有阴谋，如果你知道我的意思。
No hanky-panky.
Regular habits,
as far as anyone knows.
呃，日常习惯嘛。几乎没有人知道 甜药好入口
The medicine go down
甜药好入口
Just a spoonful...
只要一汤匙糖 是他！
It's him!
帮你把苦药…… 或者声音听起来像是他
Or something similar.
A little less noise on the premises.
服下 班克斯夫人，能不能让房子里的人小声一点
我听不到警长的声音了 他现在很兴奋
I can't understand the inspector.
Just a spoonful of sugar
只要一汤匙糖
让苦药服下 乔治！
Makes the medicine go down
You didn't jump in the river.
哦，乔治，你没有去投河
How sensible of you.
你真明智啊
It's all right, sir.
好了，先生，找到他了！
He's been found.
不，还活着！
No, alive,
或者我以为。他正在亲吻班克斯夫人
or so I presume.
He's kissing Mrs Banks.
What happened at the bank?
我真的很担心，在银行发生了什么事情？
I've been sacked, flung into the street.
我被解雇了，赶了出来，扔到了大街上
A spoonful of sugar
一汤匙糖能让苦药服下
Makes the medicine go down
他刚才的行为有点不正常
Gone off his crumpet,
that's what he's done.
甜药好入口 疯疯癫癫的
Dotty as you please.
乔治，你在地下室到底在做什么？
What were you doing in the cellar?
First, where are the children?
一会儿你就知道了。孩子们在哪里？简？迈克尔？
Jane! Michael!
Your father's calling.
你们的父亲在叫。 听起来不像是父亲的声音
It doesn't sound like Father.
Jane! Michael!
简？迈克尔？ 快跑去吧
Run along. Spit spot.
You won't go, Mary Poppins, will you?
你不会走吧，玛丽?泼平斯？
Spit Spot.
快！快！
He mended it!
他修好了！
It's wonderful!
太好了！ 你怎么修的？
However did you manage it?
With tuppence for paper and strings
花两便士买了纸和绳子
You can have your own set of wings
双脚站在地上
With your feet on the ground
你可以让风筝拥有自己的翅膀 紧紧抓住绳子
You're a bird in ?ight
With your fist holding tight
你就能像鸟儿一样飞翔
To the string of your kite
来放飞你的风筝吧
Oh, oh, oh
吼，吼，吼
Let's go ?y a kite
让我们去放风筝
让它飞向空中的最高处
Up to the highest height
Let's go ?y a kite
让我们去放风筝
And send it soaring
让它在空中翱翔
Up through the atmosphere
穿越云层
Up where the air is clear
直达晴朗的天空
Oh, let's go fly a kite
哦，让我们去放风筝
A proper kite needs a proper tail.
你不认为，一个好风筝需要一条合适的尾巴吗？
That's what I said.
那是我说的，先生。去放飞风筝！
Go fly a kite.
哦，不，先生。我不是说你
No, sir. I don't mean you personally.
Let's go ?y a kite
让我们去放风筝
让它飞向空中的最高处
Up to the highest height
让我们去放风筝
Let's go ?y a kite
And send it soaring
让它在空中翱翔
Up through the atmosphere
穿越云层
直达晴朗的天空
Up where the air is clear
Oh, let's go fly a kite
哦，让我们去放风筝
When you send it ?ying up there
当你高高地放飞风筝
All at once you're lighter than air
立刻你会感觉自己比空气还轻
你能在吹过房子和树林的风里起舞
You can dance on the breeze
Over houses and trees
用你的手紧紧握住绳子
With your fist holding tight
To the string of your kite
系上你的风筝
放！
Oh, oh, oh
让我们去放风筝
Let's go ?y a kite
让它飞向空中的最高处
Up to the highest height
让我们去放风筝
Let's go ?y a kite
让它在空中翱翔
And send it soaring
There you are, Banks.
班克斯，你在这里啊
Congratulations.
我要祝贺你
Capital bit of humour.
绝妙的笑话。叫史密斯的木腿
"Wooden leg named Smith,"
or Jones, whatever it was.
或者琼斯或者其他
Father died laughing.
父亲在笑中死去
Oh, I'm so sorry, sir.
噢，我很抱歉，先生 不，没什么可抱歉的。
Nonsense. Nothing to be sorry about.
Never seen him happier.
在他的一生中从没有见他这么快活过
He left an opening for a new partner.
他留下了一个新合伙人职位的空档
Congratulations.
恭喜了
Thank you very much indeed, sir.
谢谢你，先生 真的谢谢你
Up through the atmosphere
穿越云层
直达晴朗的天空
Up where the air is clear
Oh, let's go
哦，让我们一起
去放风筝
Fly a kite
Awk!
That's gratitude for you.
这需要感谢你
Didn't even say goodbye.
甚至没有说声再见吗？ 是，他们没说
No, they didn't.
Look at them.
看看他们，你知道，你跟他们的父亲相比，他们更想念父亲
They think more
of their father than of you.
That's as it should be.
那是自然 好吧，你不在乎？
Don't you care?
Practically perfect people
never permit sentiment
近乎完美的人从不允许在他们的思想中掺杂个人感情
to muddle their thinking.
Is that so?
真的是这样？我告诉你，玛丽?泼平斯，你别骗我了。
Mary Poppins, you don't fool me.
Really?
真的？ 真的！我完全知道你对这些孩子们的感情
Really. I know how you feel.
If you think
I'm keeping my mouth shut...
如果你会认为我继续保持沉默，我……
That will be quite enough, thank you.
那就乖乖地闭上嘴，谢谢
Goodbye, Mary Poppins.
再见，玛丽?泼平斯。别离开太久
Don't stay away too long.
Oh, oh, oh
吼，吼，吼
让我们去放风筝
Let's go ?y a kite
让它飞向空中的最高处
Up to the highest height
让我们去放风筝
Let's go ?y a kite
让它在空中翱翔
And send it soaring
穿越云层
Up through the atmosphere
直达晴朗的天空
Up where the air is clear
哦，让我们一起去
Oh, let's go
放风筝
Fly a kite